hello my lovely listeners happy whatever
day of the week it is that you're
listening to this I just wanted to give
you a heads up I'm starting out this
episode a bit different I'm gonna let a
song play from the group that is a guest
on this podcast right now that you're
listening to so this is called - also
known as baseball from rows 10 you can
find them at rows 2 and Bandcamp
whatever you're doing right now I hope
that that you're thinking about yourself
in a positive manner I hope you drink a
little bit of water I hope you're trying
to eat right trying to sit up straight I
mean enjoy this a couple minutes of this
song and then we'll float it right into
the podcast Cheers friend thanks for
listening
[Music]
she's a kiss of sunshine she tells me
that I'm handsome step-by-step I'm throw
me some fish like ass baseball playing
no game I want it all I used to be
frozen in the summer this was supposed
to be
[Music]
better luck next year
leaves are turning red
[Music]
whether gay
[__]
[Music]
better luck next year
is it
[Music]
Eric Nordine so distracting
Eric Rodina froze Tim you want to just
open this podcast up with your toe
what's going on buddy
broke my toe it hurts
swelling it kind of feels like it's
bubbling inside of it and I'm wondering
if I'm like in trouble here man oh it's
okay well cheers to that because you
know it helps injuries right there's old
like a civil war medicine yeah there we
go
so guys we have rose tan with us today
and poor Eric he unfortunately was
changing his tirely ur tire earlier and
had a mishap
so his toe is a bit on the hurdy side I
like the thought of him hurting his or
like doing his tie and then he like
hurts his toe somehow yeah just like
putting a knot how do you think that
would happen well I think you could do
it it requires a lot of attention to put
on a tie I don't know I don't know how
to do it you don't know how to tie a tie
I can show you a tight tight buddy all
right let's do it
I actually worked at a mr. Foreman
tuxedo nice you definitely yeah but for
the most part we just had not the
clip-on ties but they were like go
around on one side and they were in it
they zip right the zip ones too like you
put around your neck and you can just
like cinch them up I've never had any of
those but yeah yeah just like but it's a
lot classier if you tie your own tie
though I think it is yes and there's a
lot of different not so you can learn as
well yeah like I'm ship has sailed I
think from
I think you're very definitely travel
down that road you think you can teach
an old dog new tricks I think you
definitely so guys we have this is the
band roast and we also go by Jake Eric
Jake's and Eric there is three Jake's
and one Eric I'm not even in the band
but I hang out with these guys a lot
this is a band that I hang out with
quite often they're they're starting out
but they're really freaking good
they're they're a bunch of very talented
musicians and very good people and I
have the privilege of hanging out with
them once a week at least right yeah
thank you as we can I would say yeah
yeah at the very least and so you guys
let me tag along and you take my input
and we work together on a bunch of cool
stuff it's it's it's pretty cool it's
it's definitely teaching me a lot
working with musicians it's something
that you know we're working with a lot
of DJ's is is so great and you learn a
whole different side of the music world
but working with more musicians who are
who have instruments in their hands and
and more on the vocal side of things is
just teaching me so much so I appreciate
you guys tonight I definitely want to
talk about the beginning of a band how
how does a band even start like what is
it how do you even start a band what
even happened
well I I think kind of that too Eric
honestly just like let him know yeah
it's weird
I think like the branding of Rose tan
itself I think came from I was tired of
putting on music as Eric Nordine I had
like a frustrating amount of ego
connected to like what I was doing and
then so when you fail at what you're
doing or wouldn't you perceive yourself
as a failure at what you're doing then
like having your name on that is like it
like a crisis and stuff like that and I
think removing my name from it also
removed an expectation of being like
Eric Nordine he's like guitar player or
Eric 13 he's that and stuff it's like
you give something in name it
now a new creative something over here
so it's a new new thing okay and so I
did that and like I made a little
Instagram page and I had like 24
followers and made some really weird
experimental stuff that was aggressively
influenced by like the new bony their
album really weird experimental stuff
harshly auto-tuned you know trying to
reach out there and do weird things but
it was when I started trying to demo
vocals without auto-tune and someone was
like that's actually pretty good and
then you start doing that live and then
I just started realizing that like I I
don't think that what I was doing is
still the whole goal is like be honest
and rebranded in a creative direction
and even though I had done that I wasn't
like fully doing it and so once I fully
surrendered the idea of this isn't gonna
be a solo project I got to get band
mates I think that's when the band
really started and stuff and then Jake
Wilson weed weed I played like a lot of
tap houses and just our hometown alone
view and stuff and so I could play like
a you know Ashe town antidote Tap House
and then in kilometers whoo that's first
yeah yeah and that's where we started
playing together probably it's kind of
reached out to you randomly it was like
hey cuz like I knew I knew we could
improvise and jams like a couple hours
and we just get some free beer in the
noise summer so we did that it what a
great gig as a great gig right and so
Sam some dogs yeah yeah yeah well yeah
actually that was like right after I had
just met I had just met Eric like right
at the beginning of summer I would say
like early June and we kind of just like
connected over playing guitar we're like
oh will you play guitar
oh me too that's all and then Eric was
like hey come on down to Willy Dix and
hang out I'm gonna be playing guitar
there and I was like great I'll come
down I have some fun listen to some
music yeah yeah some fun
yeah I was like July aresome yeah it was
really early summer so you guys bought
it over hot dogs yeah yeah what do you
do yeah man like peanut peanut butter on
a hot dog Willy Dix
I don't miss around there anyway I went
down there and I met some cool people
and I listened to Eric and Jake Wilson
play guitar and I was like wow these
guys are awesome
the really good musicians and just
really cool people and I hope some day
that we can get together and make music
together and then that that was like
back in July and then like just fast
forward to September yeah I guess we
started rehearsing in September to
scramble for October show yeah right
or was it scrambling in October to play
in November it was definitely our first
shows Dec definitely just how did you
guys even determine how to cuz like Eric
obviously you have a bunch of songs
under your belt at this point oh okay
but so you you just you just hit up
these guys like meet up did you know
that you were talking about Rose tan
about yeah the whole thing is like I
think it's important to go into
something with a pretty big creative
vision I think it's also okay to go into
stuff with oh yeah that's the whole
point okay come around full circle for
myself here the whole point is like
playing songs and a medley of rebranding
with Rose tan was also like removing
expectation okay
removing expectation of like we're going
to get together and we're going to make
it that like totally like puts a
terrible over view of like what you're
gonna do artistically what you wouldn't
know what we're going to do is gonna
hang out become the best young man that
we can at that time and we're gonna sing
some pretty fun songs and whatever
happened like maybe we're just a band
for a year and that's a really fun here
like that's awesome
or maybe career happens out of it like
either way like it's such a powerful
mindset to have with this thing
definitely as Eric was saying earlier
just like kind of the open mindset when
Eric first came to me like I I didn't
even know he was asking me to be part of
Rose ten he just he
said hey do you want to hang out and
play some guitar and I was just like
yeah sure and so so we met up that that
first night and then just like it kind
of just rapidly very rapidly snowballed
from there
well like the there's the panic of the
fact that I had a show but there's also
like there was a point of necessity
which is how it came to be one of days
because originally there was the idea of
having it be a full band and yeah and
there's still like some nice for tatius
ideas of doing like full band versions
of something on an album but there's
something unique about taking an
acoustic acoustic ish trio like this and
the different kind of spaces you can
play and the different energy you can
bring we can play small rooms and make
that remove like heavy and emotional we
can play big rooms to make that big of
emotional we can play a small room and
just be that nice thing in the corner
like you know which is what will be like
when we're probably traveling out a
little bit you know but then like so
there's some shows where it's like we'll
be on stage that's a show with other
artists and stuff and that's when the
set changes from playing in a brewery
for like an hour to that we have a
scheduled our thoughtful set you know
kind of DJing stuff is up as opposed to
like I'm gonna you know free ball while
all these people drink for four hours or
it's like are you playing a set with
several other DJs right you gonna put
together a whole like right yeah if
you're doing some sort of like headliner
I have an hour slot or some sort of like
opening set or something it's different
than playing background music or like
like the musical version of like
submitting yourself to the elements you
know and just like all these different
environments and they're you just kind
of learn to grow inside of them yeah
yeah you guys are very good at that too
it's the feel honestly it's just like we
can feel like moments it's like I would
say like when we are doing like show
stuff like deliberate show stuff like
when we like we will kind of just I
don't know it's the whole thing we just
kind of vibe off of each other we all
look at each other like all right do we
need to kick it up a notch right now or
would that be kind of inappropriate for
the the vibe of the room right now for
us to be right blowing the roof off this
place yeah do I get
see that really good to like I even just
in practice like when I'm over here
working on stuff and you guys are behind
me on chimed in once in a while I give
my opinion but like you guys can pick up
this vibe it's like sometimes Eric will
come in and be like hey I got this it
feels like a crap day and I wrote this
song and you guys like we're in it
that's it let's hear it and in it you
just pick up the vibe and you guys have
this it's a cool thing that you know
it's it I it's very cool to me to be a
part of it because I'm not in the band
but I kind of get like this cool band I
get to see you guys look at each other
and communicate without words like
that's something that it's a front as an
outsider it's like wow that's cool ya
know and that's totally valuable and
it's like it's important and essential
for a lot of bands who actually like
have that person cuz like the Beatles
had George Martin you know right and
like that guy was like there all the way
until like he died you know those guys
just being like hey you know how can I
help you like what can I do for your
career and like like that's that's what
you've been doing the entire time
because like even before me and Jake
were in this like it was you and Eric
had produced that EP together and like I
mean Eric spoken of your influence on
that and how you just kind of worked
with him on that sort of like strip back
atmosphere and kind of like help you
like oh you know I guess like guiding
the flow in some ways and like that's
that's important you know because the
listeners ear is part of the musicians
ear yeah yeah definitely thanks for
saying that it's something that I'm like
learning more and more because it starts
out as just hanging out and Eric's like
you want to help me with this thing and
I'm like I sell myself short a lot I'm
like the I don't know like like I don't
I don't want to come over here and think
that I can like help you with it or
whatever but then you know ends up
making this like wonderful three track
who's to compete yeah yeah but yeah it's
really cool to find your place and just
but again not really trying to do it
that this whole thing has been like
let's hang out with your friends and
have a great time yeah let's let's let's
let's just try to get a little bit
better at these things and let's let
your friends input help you and like
eric has just made me so much better
than so many of the things that I
already thought that was super good at
just by hanging out with him and being
next to him be like oh he's crazy good
at that thing cuz he does that
well thanks man that's really nice he I
think that the biggest thing going back
to the expectation thing is like I had
kind of thought earlier like you know
we're but we're going into the new year
and there's a few artists that I like an
artist out of Dallas Texas that I
produce for and she and she's a she's a
great talent okay but last year I
remember on Twitter she's like 2019 is
gonna be the year for my music and I
mean the years over and she had a great
year for like releases and stuff but
like guess what she didn't like have a
big breakthrough and stuff and I think
there's an I think it's great to set
goals but I think it's really important
to have a sense of reality of like the
steps that it takes to get to these
goals as opposed to a ludicrous view of
like late like to say like 2020s year
that roasts and makes it is a year that
like would probably the collapse of the
morale of the band alright because it
could be alright shooting for the wrong
goal yes correct
you should be what like am I in my
opinion and what I'm working for
personally and like I think of the band
is good is that in 2020 the goal is like
I'm going to become a better person and
a better musician perfect great the
template is in place for that to be
successful for it to fail would be a
huge mistake on one of our ends most
likely would be something on my end
being the bandleader and even being the
one who is probably like the most
unstable in certain facets of life and
stuff but I think but I think there's
been like lay it but like for me
personally like there's been a lot of
growth in recent months and like a lot
of has been because like being in this
band and being being a band leader is a
really crummy term but like as far as
its wired but it's the only thing that
explains what's going on really I'm kind
of like just judge and for now that's
what it is to like because for now like
so far I've been bringing songs to them
but now and and the songs from the
acoustic EP live have been wonderfully
embellished right and then they're gonna
have stuff to brain to me like Jacob
Carroll just like
to some he showed me like before the
podcast started that's great Jake Wilson
shows me a bunch of stuff that he's
written you know so there's more things
to tap into then like then my sadness in
2019 you know but that's what because
that's what got you guys like it it's
like hey I I can get this whole thought
out now it got you guys together and so
just how old you guys are to whatever
happens next we're gonna just see what
happens with it like not having these
goals do you guys think that that a lot
of young artists get too caught up in in
the fame like do you think they like
because I heared a lot of times a lot of
times onlookers who aren't artists who
aren't musicians who aren't they don't
understand and they'll say things like
like oh one song you can get famous or
one more hit and you could be the one
and things like this and in in that
mindset is always really weird to people
like us I'd say because we're like what
like that's not the gold though the goal
is to love life and play music with
friends right yes like definitely what
you said like just like loving life and
enjoying the music and enjoy making
music with your close friends like like
we're doing right now like like I really
love what I really love about this is
just like we're bandmates but we're also
like we enjoy spending time together
like that that's super important to not
get together and hate each other and
have to make music sort of like like an
arms race yeah yeah and like I don't
really feel like there's any competition
in between us like we're all working
together and then like we have this
amazing person
Jake Ryan's with us like like like you
said about that Beatles guy earlier just
like he's that constant sort of like oh
I like what you guys did there oh maybe
you guys could like do that part a
little quieter and me and so we're like
we're really open to a lot of input -
and back to what Jake said yeah it is
it's an interesting thing like a lot of
people like like especially outside the
music like so one more hate one more big
song you know it's like it's like that
was like the big the big shock for me
cuz honestly this this is my first
experience in like an actual like band
band like playing music I have been
doing serious band things
and Eric has been so good at being
realistic like because after after our
first show and like just like incredibly
positive feedback from people close to
us and people who have never talked to
before it was easy for my mind to just
be like that's it man
we made it this is it this is it a
Hollywood here I come there was a talent
scout at that Tap House for sure we made
it boys and then Eric was just like we
got back down into like we got back down
practicing again and Eric it was just
like all right on to the next show what
do we got next let's write some more and
it was like incredibly just like oh
that's how that's how it works in
reality it's not we make one song we do
one performance and that's it we made it
boys like and then like I feel like a
lot of people can get discouraged like
that like they make one song and like
maybe it gets like 20 plays on
soundcloud if they're lucky and they're
like music so it's not for me you know
yeah your music sucks if you're going
towards the wrong goal if you if that's
how you're what's how you're weighing if
you're doing well or not of course
you're gonna have bad measurements that
I think like music in social media and
things like SoundCloud as like a musical
social media and a platform I I think
they're like social tools now and I
think like to younger generations and
and not to like separate myself from
younger generations but I feel like
people younger than us don't look at
music the way people like 30 years ago
or 50 years ago or however long picking
up instruments and having to like
actually do it like they're not looking
at it the same way I think it's more of
a social tool and that's why it's more
like check this out come see my song
just go see it you know yeah it's weird
it's like the it gives people in my
opinion everyone should have the freedom
to post and upload any sounds they want
and that's important but I also think
that people get and an unrealistic
feeling of like like like there's like
the first time you make an official
Spotify for yourself like for your own
self and stuff you're like I'm [__]
signed bro I got a blue checkmark on my
goddamn even for that yes when I saw the
junk I love podcasts on Spotify and the
branding is big and and that and and it
took effort to do it and therefore yes
that's good but it's it's then it's then
the taking that success part of like
okay I have achieved this and then going
further with it where it's like I have
achieved this and I'm all this and a bag
of chips going oh you know way off of
the rail with it where it's like you
have to be realistic about where you are
currently in the steps moving towards
things I think um I think I think in
music there's a really important analogy
than like a staircase right so there's
like there's I want to be a musician and
then at the at the top of the staircase
there is like I am a famous whatever
like if your goal is to be famous right
okay the stairs going up to that are
like necessary things how a mentor or a
teacher teach you some things learn
about things that like learn from
someone who is better than you
consistently surround yourself with
people that are better than you practice
for more than a year I mean like to get
good at guitar the way that I did to get
a scholarship to college it's not like I
play guitar for a few months and posted
for you on YouTube and I felt really
good about myself so they gave me a
scholarship my family spent a lot of
money on private lessons for me I was
lucky enough to have parents that wanted
to fund me as an artist and as a young
high school you know what I mean like a
lot of parents like screw that you're
definitely putting some numbers on the
board at a young age I mean you've been
you've been talented from a very young
age
yeah well but that's still only because
of teachers though I didn't have a lot
of raw talent I think I think on a good
rot year well III think meaning from
from the parents perspective of like oh
[__] this is something we should put
some money to right right well I'm
making it worth their time and worth
their money like they knew the after why
didn't you put in your work to prove
this right yeah okay so to go to that
point like I started taking lessons here
in town from longtime local legend Bob
Nelson okay he's a great guitarist
he got he got me I can and he started me
off we fly I loved dissonance which is
like clash II stuff in music and because
it pulls out emotion to me I loved it I
found a lot of dissonance in Latin jazz
bossa nova Brazilian jazz Antonio Carlos
Jobim is a girl from ipanema blue bossa
sounds like songs like that where the
court changed her color changes are so
thick and insane and very dissonant he
got me into that and then eventually I
still had to uh I had to go on to
another teacher like I had another tier
that I knew had to go up on right and so
then we took I took lessons from a
Portland jazz international jazz guitar
current not legend I would say but
Northwest legend Dan Ballmer and and
he's he teaches at Lewis and Clark
College and he travels internationally
plays for other people too and he's
someone who has a solo career in place
for people like he's so that's who I
learned from a lot in Portland and he's
someone that consistently I think was
like three or four lessons and he's like
you're not that good it was awesome it
sucked I was like really frustrated I
remember my freshman year in college I
would still take lessons from excel was
going to Mount Hood community
you know I go see him and I would get in
the car and call my dad like still in
the in the dude the driveway crying like
real human tears frustrated because I
would cuz he just feel like this and he
just he just wouldn't stop but he would
keep counting up a tune too fast and I
couldn't start Chris couldn't write I
would freak out right like get home I
would ignore my guitar for a few hours
and bike okay I got to practice that
song before rehearsal tomorrow at school
and then I would do that and then
whatever he was telling me at the lesson
let me just click all of a sudden and
it's like this dude's it's so good he
does crazy so just sitting on the
information like not even realizing that
you were holding on to it for later
right and then you get to playing again
and it comes out you're like damn it
nice yeah it's genuinely insane it's a
wonderful teacher there yeah man and
then Brian Mitchell mark Moore's choir
director was probably the biggest
influence in my developmental stages of
life as a young kid as a young artist
and stuff like
because he showed me like this choral
music where everything was cluster
chords which like basically a cluster
chord and acquire is he divided the
choir into a lot of sections and you
almost have every note on a scale being
sung at once and it causes a harmonic
swirl and it makes you make sure it
makes your spine tingle and goosebumps
it's a crazy amazing experience he got
me into stuff like that he was also the
jazz choir director and stuff and so he
got me into really weird free form
improvisation Miles Davis [__] brew
so at a younger age I'm digesting pretty
heavy music that's like stuff to study
that like in college like I was taking
college music theory when I was 16 and
but it's not but and I think that's
because I found success in music quickly
because my teachers were so good right
that like that's a really big thing to
to like I'm
yes I put in work I put in time and
practice but they told me to practice
they showed me what to practice they
told me to move all I needed to move on
I went up and up and then they gave me
the tools to when I went up to Seattle I
could I could work under some really
really cool people right it's because I
and they gave me those tools if I would
have if I would have went up there with
raw talent not being able to identify
what things are and not know what I was
talking about there's no way these
opportunities would've come you know
what you're talking about in the audio
world that's why you have great jobs and
you can yeah but I go you wouldn't go to
your world and I don't know what you're
talking about
but same George though that's like if
you if you go set up this festival I'll
be like that's and then you're like
playing a major and I'm like that's like
kind of like what we all do here what we
all bring to the table when we're and
just dab but I'm trying to form a thigh
here so we're all literally at a table
so I bring to the oh yeah well we all
bring something unique and we talk about
a lot here and it's just like it's so
cool getting to make music with these
guys all of all four of us
bring something unique to the table
whether it's theory whether it's the ear
whether it's the feel whether it's the
emotion or the the sound tech even like
stuff like that or just the opinions the
outside ear everything we bring is so
valuable and it's incredibly obvious
when one of us can't make it to the
practice like something's missing like
it doesn't feel complete it's like the
the cheese isn't on the pizza it's like
it's like on the sauce crust
it seems worse I'm glad none of you guys
are the pineapple for that pizza you
know you know yeah Hawaiian pizza was
like my first love we got it pepperoni
he's a cheese beat yeah but you guys
here's something that everybody needs to
know what is that if you fried Brussels
sprouts
what no listen to this fried Brussels
sprouts dude Porky's has those fried
Brussels sprouts but what's amazing is
that the size and shape and consistency
of these little crispy circles are like
little tiny like pop-up beets crispy
pepperonis oh wait okay
I mean they have that salty taste yeah
you could totally have a vegetarian
pizza shop just sell these [__]
at the store
no dude you call a fry cauliflower crust
as well now wait actually now we're
getting to the mere people what people
wanted to hear the lack of meat of what
people wanted yes
look at that chair just went down yes
that chair is gonna be a hatred of but
so people who have been listening to my
podcasts watch watch your head he missed
it whoo Eric is sitting in the chair
that just randomly loses its hydraulics
and just starts going down but so which
now the people listed my podcasts often
know about that chair cuz it's been in
the last five well I well I'm honored to
be a part of this the meme when are you
going to have the chair as a guest can
you guys step outside we'll just do a
little yeah just leave the jet follow on
twitter has its own podcast build cast
and there's a half hour of that cat
consistently purring welcome well miked
and compressed it's one of my favorite
it's like well I already I already want
my own kitty so bad I I want my I want a
little kitty that I come home to and I'm
like what up Paul and like I'll go get
my five and he's like I had a good day
it's like I had a good day too now I can
release my stresses and pet you very
calmly and lovingly and you're my little
guy I'm going through that I think about
cats is they're so unpredictable it's
you're like this is the sweetest cat
ever and then it gets older and it just
it hates you and you're like what am I
gonna do I'm a habit I have this cat I
have this cat named Frank and he's he's
huge man he's a tank he's Frank Frank
the tank shoutout Frank
yeah he's a he's a he's a chunk of a cat
and he's a sweetheart like he will seek
you out
like that's not cat behavior usually
like like he will you open the front
door and he comes to you like he's a dog
he's confused I think I think what
happened was we took him away from his
mom too early you know and we had a dog
in the house you know and I think he was
raised by the dog and so now Frank about
being taken away from your mom
Oh Eric man you couldn't make me cry on
the podcast no it's not true actually
it's like a wildly inaccurate fact about
my life that I need to quickly correct
go on about your cat that goes to you
when he calls no he's a sweet he's a
sweetheart and I love him and his name
is Frank that just reminded me because
you said you would name your cat Paul
and like everybody's like why would you
name a cat Frank like that's so odd
that's a human name but and I'm like
what human name yeah yeah well why do we
why do we put limits on what we name
animals right so this is actually super
great I have two cats they're not
technically mine but I do put cat food
out and they hang out in my backyard um
one is named one's name is Steven he has
a yellow eye and a blue eye he's super
cool and the other one's name is Glenn
and he's just a black cat
Glenn and Steven Glenn and Stephen Glenn
Steven Frank and Paul they're all gonna
get together and play poker homies yeah
and it's cool it's funny because like
all jokingly make up these names but in
the back of my head I'm like I know this
is gonna make Shaylee laugh a little bit
sticks like it's like cuz when I tell
her she does laughing Lee huh and so she
can't help it when she pulls in the
driveway and there's some like cat
dropping across she's like dammit
no hey Jacob Carroll yes sir want to
give me a little bit of your background
in music like how long have you been
been playing music so you've been doing
guitar alright do you play any other
instruments do yours yeah yeah my dad
actually bought me a guitar just a just
a simple squire you know real cheap
starter guitar for my I think it was my
10th or my 11th birthday he bought me
and I was like you know of course I'm 10
or 11 so I'm I'm super into like we'll
get to that we'll get I'm not 10 by the
way disclaimer I'm not 10 years old if
you're listening I'm not he's dead
alright anyway yeah my dad got me a
guitar for my 10th or 11th birthday I
don't remember and he's like you learned
how to play you learn how to play blues
guitar and I'll buy you any guitar you
want
he said that to me when I was 10 or 11
years old did you like the Blues at that
time though like did you um I spent a
lot of time with my dad and like pretty
much every time we were hanging out
doing stuff in the garage anything like
that he had BB King Stevie Ray Vaughan
even like Jimi Hendrix playing in the
background we were doing stuff you
should write a song called dad and lacks
the blue yeah we could write a blues
song that's just called daddy's favorite
daddy's favorite and it's about me right
yeah anyway yes yes yes so anyway
I was like super into it and I got
frustrated super early because I
couldn't play like Jimi Hendrix right
off the bat and a guitar I hurt my
fingers and I hated it and it sucked so
I hung it up for years I was like guitar
sucks I hate it I'm never gonna be good
at this yeah yeah it's hard to suck at
stuff if you're listening to this it is
hard to suck at stuff going but keep
going keep going because you will have
to suck to get better exactly point you
that go through a stage of suck exactly
yeah you have to suck at stuff this is
one of the most motivational like some
Instagram girl needs to turn that to
take it and make a valuable quote with
somebody walking in a like like retro
filter like like down a pathway like
with a quote you know I am set up by the
[__] that I post everywhere is just so
set up for this opportunity
be brave you suck at something new it
sucks to suck it suck I loved that one
before you picked up the old guitar oh
wow
I was probably I dabbled a little bit
like in high school I picked it up again
I learned a few pentatonic scales
you know just do-do-do-do-do-do yeah and
I thought I was just the man
and then like I could play just a few
notes and a few riffs and I hung it back
up until I was like 19 or 20 and then I
met this dude I went to college with and
he was light years better than me at
guitar his name was also Jake so
automatically made him a cool
automatically made them cool Eric have
you heard of him Eric no comment from
Eric anyway we started playing together
and he liked Eric with star players
named Jake
Jake's just whispering over their videos
whispers break though it's like he was
trying to think of what Jake is hell
it's just a bunch of Jake's saying Jake
you know what if you had unoriginal
parents and you were born in the 90s
your name is Jacob all right so anyway
yeah I started playing with him he's
like yours better than me really
influenced me to pick it back up to pick
it back up again and I kind of been
playing ever since then and then I met
mr. Eric Nordine and mr. Jake Wilson who
are also incredible musicians and it
keeps me motivated
so you didn't you didn't have any like
background like any training or do you
think that I took guitar lessons for
like two weeks
oh [__] how'd that go and it was
terrible really yeah it was like this
dude like he just like had this Walmart
guitar instruction book and he put it in
front of me and I couldn't read sheet
music and he would just solo the whole
time while I struggled to play mary had
a little lamb going back to teachers
like that's why kinda mentor like that's
why I give praise to my teachers so much
it's like we got some guitar you can
play pentatonix he can play pentatonic
so listen who's gonna be in the Chase
Bank when I need to cash my money order
from George Strait what's what for
$15,000 paid on that feature guitar boy
but yeah but yeah III saw the nursing to
here you took I don't know that about
you I didn't know you took a couple
weeks of lessons and that sucked
because I've heard so many people like
what we'll start lessons
yeah piano is a common one too with this
white will those start lessons and the
teachers bad enough where it's nufs out
the wants to even play this instrument
exactly what happened he would just sit
there and play ac/dc licks while I'm
struggling to learn mary had a little
lamb and just like it was just like this
sucks I hate this I'm never coming back
again you guys I never took private
lessons but I started taking violin in
fifth grade I did Orchestra and all I
ever did was Orchestra up through a
sophomore year and and like I had the
greatest teacher the whole time
mr. Williamson over at a Kelso and a
countyman dude that guy I used to piss
him off
really and also because I was so
hyperactive alright like Elmer Fudd or
something you know because he kept he
did look like Elmer whew yeah kid you're
gonna find a way to make fun of a
teacher no but like that that guy I mean
like he he did so much for me and was so
patient with me and even though like
somehow I still to this day don't think
I ever knew how to read music but I
still managed to do it because I would
write like the finger positions over all
the notes on up all of my I would go
through like I should have been writing
tab books in sixth grade because I was
going in there reading and all that
Givens guitar pro like that computer tab
with your program I looked at that a
couple times as weird yeah I I didn't
like tabs as a guitar player guitar pro
was this thing where there's a website
where most guitar players at all stages
when they're trying to learn a song they
go to ultimate guitar calm okay with
like you screen what tabs are to real
quick tablature when you look at it it
shows with a bunch of hyphens what a
guitar neck will look like with six
strings and then on those six strings it
will put a number on where a - would be
and that number is going to be the fret
that you
press down there for that being the note
now as far as a rhythm good for you know
what was cool about that is that it
makes you have to hear it and go oh
that's where that one fits in so there
is a part of learning and building some
strong connections there I think is
still I mean III tablature has cool
symbology that helps tie together those
discrepancies though like weird little
like things that represent like a band
that that program that's that's crazy
it's given me a crazy flashback because
that program is the reason I picked up
guitar again
because I gave up on it for so long
because I couldn't read music and I
didn't give a [__] to read music and so
I remember my uncle had that what was
that guitar pro that program he had it
on his computer and he was showing it to
me and I was like wow I can play crazy
train now I can play the intro to crazy
train I can play smoke on the water and
like I was playing all these songs
without having to read music and like
like obviously you get to a limit where
as a musician that's all you can do is
just play Lakes to famous songs you know
and you're not really making your own
stuff but to a beginner I believe like
tablature can be beneficial like reading
tabs as a beginner guitar player you're
having fun made some progress yes so
like I can play along with my favorite
songs and I don't have to read music or
like it will it'll show you an order of
notes that you yourself have not thought
to play yet and now you're like I now
have that in my toolbox so can we just
just you know based off the nation of
the podcast let's say person who has
never picked up a guitar for a guitar
before nowadays guitars are pretty cheap
you can get a decent guitar use guitar
whatever 150 bucks whatever a hundred
bucks yeah and they want to just like
learn let's just play around they can go
to tabs I would say would you say start
with tabs if they won't like check out
some of their favorite songs or what
would you say hey that's a that's a yeah
that's a tricky question for guitar
players because some I i'd say learn
chords I would say learn chord shapes
and and then go and learn skills
honestly
I put off skills for so long I didn't
learn skills until like a few years
until a playing guitar
and the the embarrassing thing is that
when I was first learning guitar I
looked at skills and I thought they were
chords I was like scales and chords
right so like because when you see them
on a chart they they have the same kind
of figuration so that they're all dots
on a fretboard to kind of look like
you're placing four taps listening yeah
they're their numbers so tabs work
there's a pair of six parallel lines and
it's like Eric was saying earlier the
number on the line is the fret number
that you're pressing down on the guitar
and so when you're looking at tabs just
say like six five four on a certain line
that you're playing frets six five four
like in order in the frets are so when
you're looking at a guitar the frets are
you settle this metal yeah yeah yeah
yeah and so you just count from the top
one two three four five all the way down
dude honestly just learning that for me
so so that's why I asked it what you
guys would recommend because for me if
you guys didn't know actually I played a
little guitar myself
when I was younger and that was what I
learned to do it I didn't know chords
didn't know any of that stuff but tabs
were like that like I was very
discouraged but then I looked up tabs
and well maybe put it away but but it
was to where like if you said smoke on
the water and crazy train those were two
things that I learned too because you
can look at the tabs like oh this is on
the third one one two three yeah cool so
it made me go from like nothing at all
to something so that was encouraging but
I but I mean I'm I put it down after a
few months and I didn't pick it up back
up for years so but that so that's what
reading tabs is as far as saying like
chords and scales what how would you say
you would go about learning that next
step of chords like like what's so
person who wants to pick up a guitar
just try it out how would they learn a
chord I think we should all three give
answers okay I I would say
like it depends on who your teacher is
or it depends on if you don't have a
teacher and if you're just picking up a
guitar in any sense just like like try
to emulate something that you know like
look up a song that you want to play and
then look up that chart and and make it
a really easy song that's possibly
repetitive so you're doing the same
thing over and over again and you're
locking in what those shapes are and
configurations because there there are a
lot of open chords that you just put
three fingers down and a lot of songs
where you hold those three fingers for
like five seconds you know and that's
that that's enough to get like a few
amount of beats in so you would say like
emulating your favorite songs would be a
good start if it's like for its artists
strumming chords yeah hallelujah touch
the guitar and and if you're learning
chords and then like like pick you know
just like experiment for sure but but
like try to find those spots where you
feel comfortable first so that you find
where you can fit in unless you're just
like totally like balls to the walls I'm
just gonna take this for what it is and
like do you think man I'm I'm just
trying to think like in retrospect if I
was gonna learn guitar differently what
would I do the same well what would I do
differently is very hard because like a
lot of times like I'll play something
and then people who don't play guitar
will be like wow that's awesome but to
me it's like a warm-up you know and like
to where I'm if I'm hanging out with my
musician buddies they won't even look
you know so it's incredibly it's really
weird so to answer your question I'm
gonna have to go ahead and agree with
Jake Wilson here and learn chords
especially song as you know because for
me that's what got me back into it was
being able to play you know the intro to
crazy train I'm like wow I feel like an
actual guitar player now it feels nice
but definitely after you get comfortable
with the feeling of the guitar in your
hands
your new guitar player spend a little
time with theory don't be afraid of it
it's very intimidating at first but if
you begin to understand music theory a
little bit stuff starts to click
you understand why you play the notes
that you play and why they work honestly
there's so much useful stuff on YouTube
I mean I just four hours so a lot of
times what I'll do is as I'm just like
diddling around I'll put on some sort of
like something like type in music theory
and see which one has a lot of views and
it kind of looks a feeling hit play and
watch it and just let it play like I
feel like just learning learning about
it leads into wanting to learn more and
like okay what do my fingers do next and
it's like you subconsciously seem to
start to understand it like what Eric
was talking about earlier how stuff
started to click when he was at home
after the lesson like there's been
multiple times like you were saying like
I spent a lot of time on YouTube now
learning from guitar channels on YouTube
because they're still obviously like
even if after I've been playing for 12
years there's still more to learn and
there's there will be stuff to learn
until I die or put the guitar away which
I don't think that'll happen but just
like they'll I'll be like watching these
videos and they'll be hard and I'll get
frustrated I'll put my guitar away for a
little bit and then I'll pull it back
out and be like oh that's why that's why
I play those you know it's like you're
working on it in the background the
conscious reading guitar and he's like I
learned it yet but I think by like next
Thursday like whenever run out like
whenever I'm listening to his song like
I mean the song is going through my head
but of course like my mind is just like
instead of thinking if I'm thinking
about the song I'm just like bouncing
with the song you know like I'm either
thinking about what I'm hearing which is
probably just like hearing what I'm
thinking you know that's a whole nother
right totally told ya but you just kind
of get to this point I don't know that
that whole approach of a cliff of what
whatever drop-off that was kind of made
me forget where where we were headed
with that one well well we were just
it's fine we were just actually going to
round out advice for like a beginner
then I'm really excited to hear what
Eric has to say like somebody who is
freshly picking up their first target
Squire Eric has some advice about minor
inversions some major sixth chords man
yeah by from the get-go so this is
Jessica walking through target to get
her first guitar this is who you're
talking to
oh so wait don't go to target would you
say that yeah my very first thing is do
not go do not buy a department store
guitar for your first instrument no the
reason why I'm saying this is because
it'll be painful to learn when it's time
to restring that guitar which will be
quickly after you open that box it comes
in it's baseboard wood it's it's plywood
it's a it's literal it's not even a
viable tone wood yeah bethi's and most
of those so it's it's so instead of
spending 50 at Walmart or Target it is
worth spending
ninety five to $100 at Guitar Center or
on musician's friend to Squire that's
what I started and if it's not what
about and is there any local places that
you recommend not anymore I mean III
Till's music has been you know III I do
recommend Till's in the sense I gets a
local business and like I support local
businesses but if you're starting I
don't recommend spending that much money
on your first guitar it's worth just it
making it if you if you're if you're
younger person starting you're asking
for it for Christmas I mean the way that
my dad did a lot of cool guitar shopping
with me is he would take me down and we
would spend a day goin a guitar shop so
I would play some stuff this is after
I'm a little more established though
right and then he would get a feel for
what I really liked and then he just get
something that was like based off it you
won't get anything that I played we
could get something close to it and he
like he's because he's still
surprising exactly yeah so not my
parents are incredible but whether or
not you have incredible parents the what
you want to do to start when you playing
guitar is you do not want to start with
a crappy guitar you want to get a decent
one doesn't have to be a phenomenal one
but you want your first chord to sound
good when it's successful
second of all you need to be
goal-oriented from the start so if your
goal is to learn a song from your
favorite artist then there's some things
need to do towards that if your goal is
to become a guitar player that's a
different Avenue entirely and with that
Avenue I immediately suggest that you
get a guitar teacher and and it does not
have to be a super formal thing my
guitar lessons were one half hour every
week I'd walk over to teals music from
Mark Morris high school I'd sit down
they'd say hey we just drum some stuff
he kind of correct me on some things we
wouldn't really be hammering things too
hard and and let what a good teacher
will fluctuate things will be a couple
lessons where he's hanging out getting
the vibe of you seeing like where he
needs to start and like for me when I
when I teach lessons I have a quick way
to get two or two or three chords
written on like a chord chart paper for
them with the fingering that they're
gonna take this home we're gonna easily
be able to know we did at practice and
look at that and they're gonna be able
to strum these in time until I see them
the next time and then I'll add
something to that right and then and
then with that you're building tools as
a guitar player with those tools you can
learn the songs from your favorite
artist quicker so I did you know I was
kind of thinking about that how you can
set out a song like you could be sitting
there and you could be finding out a
really cool chord you're like this is
intense I'm gonna send this to my
student and then this like like because
you've shown me some pretty intense
stuff you're like yo check this out
blant land lampblack and it's like I
mean like sometimes I can do stuff like
that but then I can never repeat it
because I look at it and I'm like I
don't have the patience to find out what
I just did
and so but but
imagine something that to a student
who's like this is canon this is Lord
and they're like I have to learn this
and then suddenly like that becomes
their dad and that like they're there 12
bar blues is this this [__] immense
evolution that you had by just like
setting them a goal do you think that's
that's beneficial as a teacher though I
like to start with that sort of like
intensity here's like I've okay like
I've played with people like like I've
played with people because like I'm a
decent guitar player like I've played
with people and I watch them play and
I'm like wow you are light years ahead
of me in like guitar playing like I
would have to practice for years like
put my my my fingers through the
fretboard daily and practice hard with a
mission like what Eric talked about
earlier to have this goal for yourself
whatever that goal may be to get to the
point where you are or or like as if you
were to teach guitar would you rather be
like all right here's an E major and
here's an a major like what do you think
or or do you want to be like here's how
you're teaching and I guess because
everybody has a different goal I mean
like even between the three of us like
as much as like this current like
combination is like something that that
we like really enjoy I'd like to be a
part of and feed into it's like
individually like we represent different
facets you know of musicality and that's
what's so cool about it and and
realistically I think we'd all fall much
more into that and then you know about
the very first lesson the way especially
for kids I always tell parents the first
lesson is always free because you want
to make sure that this kid really wants
to do this and that's why I'm gonna take
the time to make sure it's a half hour
in that half hour I will be able to tell
you if this kid really wants to I'll ask
the kids straight up did you die by that
guitar for you yeah did your dad way you
take lessons mm-hmm you will take
lessons okay I guess so okay you should
I mean if he wants to do it next lesson
that's fine but if not don't worry about
it you know stuff like that and then the
other thing to you
is with the goals like i9y
at the time a nine year old now she oh
she's probably middle school now she I
taught her some basics of guitar and I
just kind of like fizzled out and stuff
I don't think I think eventually I
didn't follow through at some point
looking back at it but but from but from
the very beginning I like I was having
her dude downstrokes
and I was showing her chords where she
can move just a couple fingers at a time
but it's doing two chord changes that
would make her verbally count 1 2 3 4 1
2 3 so already in her infancy and in the
beginning stages of music she has an
internal metronome right because these
are these are tools that I was shown at
a pretty young age where I thought if I
were to learn that even younger Wow
would have been quite incredible right
so that kind of goes back to what I was
saying is like I really wish somebody
would have told me about music theory
when I was like even like 16 it's like I
didn't even know it was a thing until I
was 20 maybe well there's a huge
misconception of what music is I know
what music is as a whole like to the
general population and then to musicians
oh definitely did you just hear a song
by Katy Perry like wow Katy Perry made a
really good song it's like she didn't
hearken back to what I was talking about
earlier how like and in this current
generation people are kind of looking at
music as a social tool like it's kind of
this point of allure and and like oh if
I can have all the right factors like
that you know that kind of be you know
which is cool I love it but why is
everyone kind of like [__] it up
yeah you know where are we shooting for
[__] that isn't us why is it good you
know it is like that would have been a
great song except and there's a lot of
like yet like younger like in high
school for me every kid wanted to be in
a band and play guitar and stuff and now
it's a lot quicker to like to like rap
over a beat really fast and upload it
I get that because there's nothing
better than showing someone something
that you made to show something that you
made friendship will send each other
[__] in our group message of course yeah
yeah like it but at this point this
points a little extended sermon I'm
trying to like no no but I'm saying it's
okay but you gotta watch it I'm saying
you got it you got a notice it dude it's
not it's not great to like function your
whole career off it right what I said no
you you were talking about just hey look
what I made how good that feels all
right yeah and that in the end that's
and that and that's phenomenal and stuff
but to to chase after you know it's also
important to know like if life actually
looks like let's say you you show your
friends if the your first song ever and
they go oh the first time you've ever
done anything that's awesome they're
gonna they're gonna do that
then a very common misconception this is
I'm diagnosing this from my history I
want to be clear I'm not making fun of
anyone for their doing I am diagnosing
these things because I have done them
myself then it is really easy to crank
out a lot more stuff and release
everything that you make and show
everyone all the time though you gotta
hear it and then you're gonna notice
that less and less people are engaging
there's a few reasons for this in my
opinion one of the reasons is it's it's
kind of music vomit at this point you
need to like like in the world of like
do like if I were to post every single
like it that's like posting every single
bit like time I'm just trying to jam you
know okay so like there's a difference
between having a lot of music and making
a big deal about every piece of music
because it's like if you every once in a
while really feel passionately and you
said kind of like mission goals for
yourself on a timeline of like oh every
so-and-so songs because I'm on a
frequency of making a lot of songs you
know like I'm gonna make this one
important and then people are gonna
follow up and they're gonna see what
precedes it or what succeeds it and it's
like I I think that's the problem I feel
like people don't put enough space
between what they think is is a big deal
and and I think there's a lot of hype
culture
every time you release a song this song
has to be the biggest part that that did
not used to be there I love you think
everything is the best and it's like
yeah okay it's okay to make something
and be like hey is this why I did today
we're confused about it though it's like
we think we need to get exactly what we
got the first time and something I've
done or maybe we've all done hey I'm
very guilty of it right because because
I open the problem with doing that is
that you're feeding into that
unnecessary competitive nature of it
where it's like the only reason to hide
yourself up is because you see something
and you want and you want like camera I
was saying that well okay okay but but I
think what you're rounding about
something I've mentioned a little bit
before garyvee actually talked about
this thing about I've used this analogy
like so so you post five things on
Instagram you have you know the four of
them they do crappy like they're but
like one in two they're they're like you
like they're your soul like they're what
you're good at like they're and then the
other things are just like you're like I
wonder if people will like these and
then so your one and two are the most
you but number four that gets [__]
five million views that number four and
it's you dancing on on spinning on your
head like it's something that you don't
really do but it's so the thing that
people like a lot the thing that gave
people like oh oh shoot you guys like
that that's what you really like a lot
like what if that's not authentically
you I think that's like I think that
like when when it's like you can put out
say like hey all five of these things
are things that I want to experiment
with but like if the public picks we
only like number four you might say okay
number one and two I thought were me but
they're trash right right right right
along with this point and the this is
why rose tan for me
what do you mean instead of the public
like I have people that are closed
creators to me that I can bounce these
ideas off of now I think the biggest
thing with me what like even my
Instagram handle for like years
Eric Nordine music I trashed that crap
because I'd sold sounds shitty but it's
also ambient boy
for the win that's right that's why I am
in my heart two eyes in reality like in
real life I know but like but creating
music by myself got me in an unnecessary
and an unnecessary competitive race
where like I was looking at other other
people creating and stuff near or
distant and the people from past people
from far and I'm thinking like like okay
then like I got a ramp up for this next
thing and realizing that being in like
your entire own lane and creating a
community around that Lane and making I
mean honestly the impact we've had on
the community and our three local shows
has been great the fact we've been able
to fill three rooms with people that
locate so we had one show and that was
great for schedule coming about right
yeah we don't know keep going on that
though yeah okay so this for me what a
big thing for me is that like is that I
like I like that self-gratification
thing that's an arms race musically we
talked all night
you touched on the earlier I literally
quit guitar for two years to start DJing
because I saw like how much people like
liked you and stuff and I was like oh no
one notices me because I'm playing
guitar so I have to become a DJ and so I
tossed years of schooling and like
something that I was like really good at
and sacrificed it for something else and
then got lost in all the wrong things
and that kind of a scene mainly like
narcotics and stuff like that like just
like making a lot of selfish deceitful
choices and then after a while you have
some problems and whatnot and that's not
everyone in that scene that is
unfortunately what became me in that
scene I just didn't I didn't have good
self control and and then with that
became trying to make beats and doing
stuff like that and even then I'm
struggling with a lot of insane mental
health issues I'm depressed I'm
constantly anxious even as a creator i'm
not finding peace and music and you're
staying a play and there's lots more
everything yep yep a-and you're not
treating yourself right
be clear I'm not sure I'm feeling myself
like necessary right now but I'm doing a
lot better and I think be the reason why
bro stands because I needed to change I
wanted to change myself musically and so
I thought rebranding myself as an
individual would be that and then I
realized that like you know I used to be
in bands I I was in a band called
telegraphy before this an instrumental
post rock band I played in bands in the
Seattle and Portland and stuff and the
community of that the camaraderie of
those people the consistent checking in
the talking to each other every day even
though even if you don't see each other
every day the the someone to talk to no
matter what the goal-oriented as a team
wanting something wanting to make
emotional music and make people feel
something unexpected or they came and
they did want that they did expect it
and they got it you know it all that
kind of stuff being able to do that is
is probably it's cool that we filled in
at the end of the year cuz it's easily
the highlight of 2019 for me already the
last the the last three months of 2019
the start of this band is undoubtedly
for me as an individual the highlight of
my year because it because these guys
have given me a reason to be consistent
in my personal life where it's like I
need to I need to work hard at work I
need to be a good man there I need to
improve myself when I work for Parks and
Rec I need to be more patient when I
Drive so I'm safer when I travel with my
friends I I want I we did a we did a
weekend trip together and stuff because
I I wanted to know what would be like to
travel with them because we're about to
do that and you know you just can't want
to know what you write long drive long
drive and just you know I I I just think
for me being in a band gave gave me a
much-needed sense of self-worth in an
area of music where there there's not a
lot of eyes or ears but the ones that
are there are like so intentional and
that's like the connection that I need
because the music
that I'm writing is not something like I
am foliat terms like it may not be for
everybody right and so far it's been
inherently like Burley sad music and
stuff and that's just something that I
have it's not that sad I mean it's I
mean nature of it of course is sad but
it's like right it's like this has more
emotion than what we're I just feel like
I don't want someone to be like I'm not
gonna listen to their music
right but just from a place where I came
from and writing it came from like an
inherently sad area and like word now
it's like like January 3rd I'm excited
to like what we're gonna play a new song
for the first time well yeah basically
when we rehearsed it a lot last
rehearsal and it's something where I was
like I have to write about like go into
I go to the beach all the time and we
did a beach trip together and I want and
my parents always took me to Fort
Stevens I got like put that in the song
right I got to put other details in my
life and I got to stop talking about
life as it's happening at me and I
should be I needed to change the
narrative as a lyricist which is an area
that I have not I'm very new to writing
lyrics like my music has been
instrumental for almost a decade so you
know this is all very new is singing
it's like I say inquire mark Morris but
singing is not something I'm very I'm
confident in at all but it's something
but it's the way that like makes this
feel that good to me will do then yeah
yeah I think that I think that just just
watching a lot of your progress like
I've known you as as a friend like we
got connected through the DJ world yeah
so I knew you at your worse yes you know
like into in now like wonderfully I get
to know you at your best to again I do
want to emphasize though like you
weren't some sort of like demon back
then or something like like you
definitely you certainly were just that
you've always been a wonderful person
you just we're a little caught up in
your vices and you're trying to get some
attention because you you know as much
as we're always trying to get attention
you know that's it's a huge thing in DJ
world is a quick tip to get it man
you guys especially especially when the
way was not strong with it to like you
know and when I was super happy to have
you and it's cool because you know we
look at these things out I was super
happy to have you like because you were
actually very good at DJ like
you think that you like didn't
contribute that much but you're pretty
good at DJ but but I think that it's
also really strange and fun to look at
these times now and think of like if you
didn't do that thing where you did the
DJing thing for a while right in and you
did learn quite a bit like on Mabon beat
making and stuff
yeah and in we like now are our pass
head cross so it's just interesting you
know it's just I like to point these
little things out because I feel like as
a listener if it's just kind of like
sometimes you don't realize that when
you're in the [__] when you're in the
mud it's like you gotta keep going
because you're learning something right
now right you know like it like maybe
somebody's in there like their their DJ
phase of being an ambien person you know
what I mean you know could be your
mother
hey you're looking a little like a DJ
man are you alright hey you're like
backwards into this I know it's too
boring joggers for like nine days
crossfading a little too much alright
guys okay that's enough this has been
the junkyard left podcast no but it's a
good point though with the past like I
think the past is still necessary
because sometimes I look back and I go
oh I wish I could have changed this or
that and this goes for more than music
this goes like personal life stuff
there's constantly you look back and you
go I coulda shoulda woulda all the time
but constantly okay but right and that's
been my that's been my biggest mental
enemy and I think it's also been
misdiagnosed depression I think I think
I call it depression and I don't thing
MN sleeve through real depression and I
realize that maybe it's it's you know I
think it's smaller nobody talked about
this later with mental health and stuff
I think as a whole we misdiagnosed
anxiety and depression eyes like
filtered on depression right like we
don't feel like the pressures really
general because look at what a
depression is it's like cuz you sort of
slice between depression and going
through a depression and being depressed
and visited prayer and there's a
difference between having anxiety and
being anxious we don't know how to
separate ourselves
from our feelings in an actual reality
when we're going about our days we don't
know how to separate that so when we
diagnose issues we can't rationally and
on the same line separate our feelings
from ourselves we can't say oh we're
we're beyond this identity you know like
the there's no medical identity for that
because it's not a recognized and I want
to say just honestly I think all four of
us can probably just say like a amen to
that
like like just going through it man
don't just become depress and can't do
anything like I could expand it man you
can expand it and see what it is
Jake Jake as a as a chick Wilson has a
really good way of poetically speaking
like there's been numerous times when
we're down here we put the guitars down
for a minute and we're just talking as
friends and then like Jake will say
something and then it takes us all like
what seems like 20 seconds plus they
just kind of sit back and digest what he
just said and we're like wow how long
have you been sitting on that like have
you been like long-ass [__] time
probably just like like and that comes
back to what I was talking about earlier
is how it just we're not strictly
together in this roast and thing for
music yeah no III think I think Rose ten
is more of like and that's the other
thing too is like it's more than music
like we're collaborating with a visual
artist consistently - I really got to
talk about this yeah say let's talk
about the community I was thinking of
Rosanna's kind of like a Brock Hampton
if you think about like not wholly but
Brock Hampton was like they're a bunch
of [__] who are just like
you're the videographer your part well I
mean we'll talk about okay I'll explain
it out so I I the community of bros
dance the exact an exact thing like that
would be boney bear
like Justin Vernon I listen to that
podcast broken record podcast with Rick
with Rick Rubin and and that was really
great and there's also other things
basically bony bear is like it's a six
person live band but it's a 25-person
art project
right here 28 some like that so visual
artists painters animators digital
artists that like are doing weird audio
stuff beyond music like how do these
people get paid that's my biggest
question because if I knew the answer to
that then I would hop on it the answer
is eventually I think I think that goes
back to that a great mentor up north
that I face for every once in awhile and
here in mind and he had the biggest
quote that he told me maybe a few months
ago which was also ironically had a
turning point for Rose tan which was
like why did you start in the first
place okay and that's why going back to
taking guitar lessons you need to make
sure you want this in the first place
and in my opinion to make sure he wants
it for the right reasons and you guys
set it up with the right teachers
because it all connects down the line
this like we as humans if there's
childhood trauma it affects us as adults
it can mess like there can be you know
some things ask you in the beginning of
the music stuff it will come up as an
issue later but you may not feel it in
the mid point but it will come up so
it's just better to take care of basic
music things early on got everyone to
look at it sure and you know I I just
think you know so this is go back to the
bonny bear artist community so that was
something I really admired okay there's
a little bit and that there's a way my
friend sai-san he does this incredible
visual art where he that there's there's
no way to describe and I think his
Instagram handles just add a sigh son
with an underscore at the end of it sy
som dude it's interesting it's it's
bizarre
I don't Kellyanne Sydow left one of his
a chalk drawings on there for like a
week
oh he oh she kept it up there huh result
her for like a week oh so he came back
the next week after he did that I was
still there oh that's right at Rose a
tan in the middle yeah but I think the
big thing is like with him he he doesn't
have any like formal training with stuff
and he and there's also not really a
genre
what he's doing I would call like it's
abstract at best - giving him a name but
he just listens to music and he goes he
mainly only draws when listening and I
think that's really powerful and so like
that's why I want to work with him and
him doing like a live canvas during one
of our sets right that's why he's been
practicing canvas painting recently is
because he wants to well I would like
him to in a situation where we're like
where we're playing our set and he's off
to the left and it's like a corner of
white sheets on a canvas he's just gonna
paint during that set at the end of it
that's that that's that's the end of it
you don't get to change that right just
like we like like like for us like
performing like you leaving it there you
know ever every performance has been
wildly different so every crowd gets
like that's four you know that I was I
was a I was actually listening to like
this stuff that we have on Bandcamp just
like in preparation for our like I like
to compare what's on Bandcamp right now
to what we play like live and during
practice and how it's different and how
it's the same picking up on stuff that I
think like we do we do really well and
stuff that's like wow that's different
in the way we do it live alright that's
different that's the way in the
recording and I think it's really
special like anybody who's ever been to
one of our live shows or let me put it
this way anybody who's ever been to two
of them got a different show absolutely
both times like like they didn't hear
the same song the same way two times
what's interesting is like the influence
and we've talked about this between like
practicing at a Stevens house practicing
with Jack at Stax and Stevens AG is is a
marvelous man fantastic guy he's really
kind he kind of gave me my start
personally just like it could
quick-quick for sure hold on to that
thought and don't lose it like for sure
don't lose it he he gave me my start at
my first open mic at 15 and he has
always encouraged me to record and stuff
and he kind of gave me the the year and
the sense of organic abstract stuff like
he kind of helped
cultivate my brain in here oh yeah but
yeah no he's he's a great guy and just
been very generous and like the same
sense that uh Jake Ryan sighs and just
like giving Rosa Tanner a chance to just
be like hey come here mm-hmm and just
like hang out you know like I'm here too
but let's just see how this works and
and and I think like Steven offered like
a lot of like really technical advice at
first which was really cool it's really
helpful especially is like like guitar
players and and he's got like the amps
all set up and he's got the mics all set
up he's like how do you feel about this
baba wawa and he's got like a blah blah
back for you oh you're like wow I'm glad
the blahs all sound the same
grunting at each other like yeah it
means so much more you know it a lot of
unorthodox things noise it's cool and as
I don't know I think it's cool just
being able to work with people you know
who are just outside of that band thing
once again oh you know where it's like
that they're not playing the instrument
but but they're like remember the band
like like Jake or Steven or you know I
mean like like talus because because we
were talking about arts with the kids
and how she creates these amazing visual
arts for us that are that are just
fantastic and like and there was one
picture I want to touch on that she made
and it was of a model Cheyenne leave
this fantastic person as well but she's
holding an apple in her hand and and the
shape of the Apple in her hand with with
the way her arms are holding it it looks
like an AR I was like ooh that's a rose
a tan yeah if it was intentional or not
like like if you've if you've been to
the roast and Instagram page like that
that's what most of it is and just like
all the stuff she created is just like
so incredible
and I actually got the privilege to meet
her a few weeks ago and she was just
like such a cool person to like I had I
had only seen her artwork and like kinda
this goes back to community I had only
seen her artwork and so I was like a
little bit starstruck sure when I met
her cuz I was just like wow like I've
been following your stuff forever you
did all this incredible stuff for the
band and like it's so cool to meet you
and she was just so humble about it
she's like well awesome and that was
that was the same with the Wildish band
from the area [__] obsessed with the
wilder said yes what's the wildest you
can hear both of those bands at Ashton
brewery January 11th that's gonna be the
last time we played together it was
something that our first two shows were
together so it's something super special
oh yeah and anyway but keep going yeah
yeah and like back with them like coming
back to the whole community thing like
working with other artists like as an
artist like guitar player myself
musician like I honestly looked up to
these Wildish guys for so long I was
like I was like I was like damn like
this good of music can come out of my
hometown like are like like and it gave
a lot of hope to me like at some point
that I could find a group of people
you're gonna do it man
like like Eric Nordine and Jake Wilson
like I could find a group of people and
we could create and of course Jake
Ryan's over here to create such good
music and then we approached our first
show and we played with them and then I
was like oh my god looks like it's you
guys it's you for real like I didn't
even realize cuz they were just like
friends like we were just hanging out
I'm like that that's one of my favorite
things about like I mean laundry music
scene is so funny because it's so small
so disorganized but when it's the thing
is the thing and then when it breaks
down it really breaks down you see the
people because they're not celebrities
but I mean like I mean in a small town
everyone knows each other and you just
kind
people doing like crap that person does
that you know cuz I've been there too
and and it's really cool when you kind
of get up front with them and like you
get to know them and if you like them or
you don't you just realize that that
like this is this is the movement that's
happening like like these people are
part of what's happening and and it is
so much better so much better when you
find out that they're just friends if
they just hang out like like like after
our first show we just straight up
afterwards we all just hung out and had
fun as people and as friends it was
wonderful to just like it's just like
watching those guys like get off the
stage and just having people and like
myself included just be awestruck at the
beautiful sounds they'd created and then
like we're talking as friends afterwards
and like we just put all that aside like
I was just like totally different
totally unreal experience and dude hey I
think that that we have something truly
beautiful here with with the town like
ours right we have it is a small town
certainly you know the Kelso Longview
Castlerock Kalama woodland like it's all
kind of like you know calots County but
it's there's all kind of like it's a
small town but it's huge like it's big
and it's right between those it's right
between Portland and so we do kind of
have like an intense small town or like
the ultimate small town right like where
the word the popular small town and I
think that being like doing what you
guys are doing by literally just being
genuine like up from the bottom II
hearts people just exploring what you're
exploring it's really creating this like
reach of communities so you guys talking
about - Lissa and slicin and in working
with me and working with Steven attack
and working with all these people is
you're kind of bringing up the the
community with you and Eric you you were
in the DJ scene for a while and so you
were also dipping into the hip-hop scene
so you know how a lot of the DJ and the
hip-hop scene it is inherently whether
they they realize all the time or not
it's kind of versus
not we're together yeah this thing this
thing is the most authentic like real
it's really like you feel you're just
watering it and it's bringing people
with you and it's I think like the
importance speaks for itself and you
guys getting like all this like this
huge toy you're about to go on that not
huge tour but but look local being
enjoyable like like hey here's what
we're doing with our life right now it's
so good like we have moments where we
text on the group message like every
couple days at least one of us is like
you know if I can love you guys like
it's it's great I mean this I think that
reaching for these things like look at
your community stop looking so far on
social media you know listener musician
please like just just look look at
what's around you look at the awesome
dude you have next to you the chicks you
have next to you the the people who are
good at this thing and that thing just
start combining I'm like hey you're a
videographer can you come over and like
teach me a couple things don't teach you
something about music and whatever and
you start making things together we all
have these little communities we forget
about because we're like let's look on
the internet and who's the hottest cuz I
won't work with it's so important that
people like look at it that were in that
position because people look so
dependently on the internet and like I
feel like people feel empowered to do
their own thing without knowing what
their own thing is by being fed so much
input you know and and I it it's
distracting because I get it myself and
like it's probably because I had an idea
of what I was doing before I was exposed
to so much internet you know I was
definitely involved in music and playing
guitar and and being like yeah before
[__] MySpace even came around you
know and like that was that dolly this
was huge for music to the seventh grade
I was in it like I was I was like
putting these emo bands like under oath
was definitely in my top 14 friends they
weren't they weren't in my top eight
friends but I was like in eighth grade
and I was like Alan need two rows cuz
I'm too cool for that
you know what's dope about my listeners
as they know my space my ages like they
had five my space hmm what a weird thing
you know because like it definitely came
around and like people are I was like
Tom came and did I don't know nothing
about that guy I just know that Justin
Timberlake was it a huge factor in
getting MySpace yeah he's bought it he
bought it and tried to revive it and
then I went bring sexy back tried to in
the Grammys failed going back to the
community thing though you know the
community thing with Rose tan is that's
also bigger than like what's happening
with Rose tan and the Rose team content
this is also something that's continuing
with like the people that we play with
right our next show we have david
robbins who's the frontman for alpine
grace they're a great local band what
I'm more excited for because I play with
him before I've heard him a bunch I know
this talent but this guy Mason the Mason
John is playing and he's someone that I
saw playing like in bands he was older
than me in high school
great great personality guy I've
honestly never seen him but such an
admirable person and in a just great
supporter yeah I would agree with that
and then like and so and he and we just
kind of started chatting he's come like
all of our shows he comes and seen in
sees me play like solo guitar in places
and he's always been so supportive now I
was like you still playing man like
let's get you up there again right
that's community right like like what's
a long time I do of course I want any
and he's like absolutely man like
definite let's do that and I think
that's like a really important thing at
any point where you have like
exclusivity I feel like you're shunning
like community because if your judgment
can determine like what's exclusive or
inclusive then then how is that a
community you know I I think I and one
thing that I truly believe is like the
best way for us to have success as a
band as a rose tan is to have our
community and to have other artists
behind us and for us to be behind then
if they want to be successful right
that's the only way it's gonna happen
if if someone like for us to get booked
at the McMinn immense venues and for us
to get greenlit by so far sounds we had
I had to have musical references I had
to tell I had to tell them who I have
played with individually to give to give
merit as to why my
and is worthy of playing those places
right kind of freaky so what do you do
what do you say I my past thankfully is
filled with I'm it's not worth the name
dropping but like my past is fill with
some really cool people and give that
through down that list and it's that
list is is a pretty visa is
unfortunately a pretty quick green light
in those conversations because we go oh
you've done serious stuff but but the
music that they even reached out to you
from so was it so far sounds that found
you guys on band campers there was
something where how'd you guys what is
so far sounds actually oh so so far
sounds of something what that would I
was hired to play guitar for a singer
out of Brooklyn playing some music that
like is just not my style right but but
it's a gig right like like being
successful in music doesn't mean like
you as an individual are busting out
numbers being successful music is having
consistent work in my opinion and so I
do a lot of gigs as I play guitar for
other people a lot and she was doing a
so far sound show and I am an ambient
guitar player by nature and stuff and so
I introduced a lot of things like that
and she wanted to do a boney bear
version of I don't wanna lose your love
by the outfield and that's where I got
the idea for one of our Arrangements too
and I just really let the whole crowd
have it there as far as my effects go
and my abilities I news and my chance to
really prove myself in front of a lot of
musicians it's a band touring through
Germany that was headlining so I just a
lot of people that I wanted to really
show like I'm talented to write this is
this is where all of that schooling all
that learning from good teachers all
those hours of practice it's four times
like that how do you find the right
moment to do that cuz that's also
another art right finding the right
moment to show off you know oh let me
flirt with you a little bit but I'm just
here for the gig Yeah right
I think the maturity comes with the more
you play you know when the space is
yours it's really hard to explain that
that's another conversation but but
specifically who watched them you can
watch it yes absolutely
oh you can deftly watch it happen on
stage it's communicating yeah it's a
blast man and it comes kind of natural
especially when you play with people
more right now with this thing it's to
hire musicians and a singer
we added an hour of rehearsal in that
afternoon and they were going through
and playing this set but the owner of
this so so far sounds it's like they're
in every major city around the world
they 400 in some something cities in the
world okay and every week like in
Portland every Wednesday there's a live
secret show somewhere so you buy a
ticket online and then the day of the
show you get sent a text or an email
with the address of where that show is
and that's where you go you don't know
who the artists are you don't know
anything about it and it's a way to get
unknown artists and traveling artists
work while touring through cities
between shows or that is their tour it's
just it's the whole idea is community
right now this is where I get I learned
from this
so put that to the side okay the booking
agent for so far Portland offered me her
contact info to me as an individual
she's like the episode niece all this
stuff and she usually they talked about
something about roast and I was like and
that it wasn't even performed at this
point I was like yeah I coos - JP that
we did know it wasn't even done yet oh I
just had that it Instagram page with 20
followers and a couple weird auto-tune
songs so I was like yeah but it's not
this I mean yeah I have something but I
will soon I will soon right so there's
always been motivation to get this done
because someone had a quote of high
level quality of booking was like I want
whatever you have okay yeah right so
it's like okay I better put that
together okay and so fast forward to a
few weeks ago I sent out like 40
something emails and one was to her and
then also going through the so far
sounds process of you know getting
verified there and whatever they do
there it's like they do a lot of quality
control like not everyone plays which is
it which is something I really enjoy
like like like like like they say if you
don't hear within 14 days you can
reapply in six months because that way
they you can't spam then make me miss
does the same thing if they pass on you
don't knock on their door for another
six months
because that also encourages you you can
get better you can get better why not I
like them that's a simple policy that
can set such a foot down
quality control is the most important
thing in all levels of content that
people are are drastically ignoring
there is a learning curve and learning
curves are necessary and every artist
goes through them but but but qual you
can try being a part of some major
production things where I was the fly on
the wall or the smallest piece of it
your perspective of quality because I
want to know what you're controlling
yeah so I I think I think I think you
would agree like you know when guitar
sounds good or bad yeah right so quality
controls to be being like no I don't
want that in the final recording just
like like cutting the fat off right yeah
choosing to have talus ax do our photos
for the Instagram page rather than me
because if I did then they baby pictures
of ham ROS ham but but but but the
quality that's white Alice did like our
first like it did did a run of photos
for us because I wanted it I wanted to
present ourselves at a level of like you
know and it takes seeing something at a
certain level to understand why
something could be a certain way and
maybe how it functions so I get that not
everyone has that luxury or opportunity
that's why I take the stuff and I'm very
grateful for the stuff and the people
I've been around and so that's why I
like I want to take that stuff that I
learn and put that forward into what
we're doing that's that's it it finally
makes sense now because since day one
I've heard you talk about quality
control a little sterile as a brand new
bandmate as somebody just getting into
the I wouldn't say the Arctic face it
guys I've been and have been in the art
for 12 years now the majority of my life
somebody just getting into like the the
meat and the potatoes of what it means
to be a good guitar player like
real in real-life situations you know
I've heard the words quality control a
lot and I'd be like does that mean not
playing wrong notes or what does that
mean
do you guys remember that scene in the
office where like they're asking Creed
they're like what do you do he's like
quality Auschwitz
I mean Quality Assurance the Halloween
episode that was like that was like a
great coincidence or like where his
characters I swear to god he's actual
Creed my favourite Creed like moment
he's like I'm going mung beans sprouting
mung beans my great my favorite Creed
moment is hold me now I'm six feet from
the edge I didn't finish my point about
community I think it's one of the most
important points I have to material
podcast you guys are gonna hop in on
that but let's go back community yeah
so the with the community thing so we
got to quality control because of like
people that I want to play with right
community also goes along with that
wanting to become friends with the wild
is already being friends with you and
then me personally I already knew a lot
of members of the wild ish and like
either going to schools and we're
playing music in their past in a past
life with enom stuff like really nice
you know just awesome dudes so wanted to
play with them knowing that they're from
here knowing that they're a part of this
community and their roots okay David
Robbins and his band Alpine Grace Castle
Rock rooted spread throughout calyx
county rooted father local musician
there's some heritage there right he has
a sense of duty as a local musician to
like he like he kind of knows the
process of things and
is david robbins yeah and in his
performance and stage presence is it is
great songwriting is actually really
really incredible to be honest there
they have a new song called batman do
and it's actually really good a super
good man i really recommend it get mad
70s vibe that's really good man they
like what just which is like i yeah it
in that and that's just something that's
why i'm excited i have david robbins
there do some solo acoustic stuff they
like to see what he can do you like when
he just like he's like and then like
take in and like for future shows you
like so we played our first show
together right and then like the second
she'll take one of the one of those guys
with me and the third she'll take
another guy from that first show and
take him with us right
or I can Ellensburg I have a friend that
I lived with in the in downtown Bellevue
and he's gonna open for us and that'll
be a part of our community and we're
going to insert ourselves and the
Ellensburg music community and there is
a good music community there because
essential Washington University and a
lot of artists apparently go there to
retire which I didn't know and they have
a couple of great venues there or they
have oh three venues that are worth your
time and money as a musician who's like
can travel and so we're gonna play one
this month and then we're gonna go back
to allensburg and February and the point
of that is that we met you this first
time I want to make an impression we're
gonna personal connections to where it's
like if you like this now we'll be back
next month guess who they're gonna bring
their friends that didn't see us last
time right and that's the sense of
community like because you want your
following to be a community you don't
want your you don't like there's like
one it's a variable thing where you get
to meet them to here's here's something
I I can boil it down to which was a
question I think about a lot is like
like do you guys feel responsibility
from from status do you do feel
responsibility from stature and and what
that elevation provides for you and what
people might expect from it like because
I think about that a lot and maybe it's
unfortunate that it determines a lot of
what I do but at the same time I don't
know what do you guys think are you
talking about holding yourself to
standards publicly like
I'm just thinking about like objectively
thinking about how people look at people
in our situation like like hey you have
a stature as someone who does this but
it's like at the same time we're also
people who are making opportunities for
us so for ourselves and that makes me
feel like I have a responsibility but I
don't know where channel that
responsibility and maybe it should be
into enriching what I'm doing I talk
about me other way yeah absolutely
jealous and I think I know what you mean
so I think you are already doing it and
what I mean is this I think what Eric
was just explaining is that Eric has had
a lot of mentors in his life and Jake
Wilson you're you we didn't I don't
think we've clarified you're also in the
Wildish band yeah I was tan and was yeah
I think that that kind of what Eric was
getting at is exactly the answer to what
you're saying it is by building this
community in by hey we have this show
here we're of course gonna bring this
guy from our community I think by
stepping up to the plate and saying hey
we're gonna do our best so guys that are
underneath us or that are next to us
right you know you definitely core of
course I mean the people people who are
gonna show building open as a headliner
the community is that we're honored
we're all yeah in a pool you know yeah
but by me but by so Jake Wilson by you
by you going into Wildish or roasts and
as you're 100% I'm gonna show up I'm
gonna really do my thing that gives
permission and that also builds the
community of the people who are watching
you people are gonna be on those next to
you before you whatever to be like okay
Jake Wilson showed out Eric Nordine
showed out Jacob responsibilities
absolute responsibility was to like my
sense of responsibility was so I get
this community going because like so in
high school I'm sure you can remember
this big even playing for a while right
like in high school there was there were
like some bands that were I doing stuff
around here me there were some shows to
go to it
yeah exactly poorly there were venues
there's Jesus where bands to go that was
really easy yeah I was watching your old
punk kid just like somehow Kenzie's
reads - world quesadilla factory open
like like we as a Merton for is open
offer from Indian Lakes up a freaking
quesadilla factory like and then like
let live was playing there a week later
and then they stopped you know I
remember - world like I was too young
good like cuz I'm a little bit younger
than you guys so like I I was too young
to go there for like shows but like I
love the place cuz they had a dope-ass
arcade in there yeah listeners was a
burger bar arcade bar and they also had
a small venue for for local artists and
they had a bunch of dope bands playing
in there I'll never forget a there was a
gamblers die broke show with see cats
and horse was there and somebody I like
there was like sharded glass on the
floor and somebody cut her foot and was
like skanking the entire night and
there's blood on the dance floor not
like the bad kind not like the bad band
from like 2011 not like the fit yeah yes
oops is it past ten o'clock is this like
Late Late Night the late-night podcast
okay listen this podcast we're just some
homies hanging out having a couple
drinks we're just we're just kicking
back we're this is a band I were a cop
[Laughter]
we're just hanging out I a really a
thing about this podcast though is
people really do like that I I get texts
all the time I get messages all times
like the authenticity we're just hanging
out we're not we're not that's the thing
about your band - is where you're not
claiming to be anything crazy you know
you're just you just like you there is
moments where Eric of course you you're
noticing like oh we are mentors right
like in wait it's like not that you're
trying to responsibility that Jake
Wilson I get it now
that's the sense of responsibility so
yes I do feel and I think we all we
already have a sense of responsibility
individual we feel that by the people
that you invite over from time to time
who like by the random people you invite
over to try to do something creative or
just to hang out and to mess around on
the stuff or the people that you take
time to go hang on strim a few chords
with and stuff like that right that that
that that is fulfilling your
responsibilities to the music community
by small actions just as like let's say
just because my I have a long background
and like courage stuff this is like your
responsibility as a Christian is not to
be like the best Christian in the world
it's like like these small acts of like
goodness are like like important and
stuff and they did not make you a
perfect person and it's not what
validates you to get into heaven it's
just like something that's like
important to do as a person right which
is like which is it which is outside of
Christianity's I don't know I put faith
on that you should just be doing good
things and like I think if there's any
any musicians listening to this or who
have seen us live or follow us on
Instagram or bangtan band yeah Instagram
cake or have just or just heard about us
or whatever just one thing there's one
thing that I've learned from these guys
and like from playing live and all that
it's just like as a musician or as an
artist or anybody sure your art man
don't don't apologize for that is one
thing that eric has taught me and that
Jake Ryan's has taught me and Jake
Wilson has taught me is if you have
something worth sharing don't sit on it
man
like like share it sure especially like
like I don't know I might have a right
reasons for the right and the right
reasons is a part of quality sterile
statement but it's about that if you
have something that's so important you
want to share it like I get that you're
not gonna become the best guitar player
in the world before you share it but
like like the people that like define
success really early on in their music
stages like people that like their first
two spotify releases a boom right they'd
blow up it's because they knew the level
of quality that had to put in for their
first statement to make if you're
showing it to
audience make sure that it's ready for
someone who's not your audience Wow Wow
that's another Jake will shot of people
I can tell that's such that such that
was that was a guy with like a reindeer
and his hand out of five best part is I
don't even remember what I said anymore
but in all seriousness I think that's
like that's that's our want and it's not
about individual praise it's about but
there's there's been a in County and
Longview there's been on a hole in music
where unfortunately uh
you know there's been a couple of
attempts to open venues by some churches
and stuff I love their heart for wanting
artists and use it to happen but art
dies in a church in my opinion like that
they're just like oh no I'm throwing it
down this is like I've been I've been
around it too much
there's standards in a stranglehold of
what you can and can't do when you
perform in this building that we have
done here and it's like so there's no
place the artist can go and truly
unapologetically do this there's a lack
of desire to support those artists from
those people it's it's waiting for
people to support their cause and and
that's dangerous like in a capitalist
mindset it's not community I know that
is socialism I said yeah I do you guys
think that it is like you know it's not
I mean on this podcast this podcast I
really talk about like the the I put my
tinfoil hat on you know I talk about
like do you have society's weirdness
I'll make you a baby
but but do you guys feel like maybe like
you know cuz you're all smart we all
listen to a ton of podcast we all talk
about like AI and aliens and all this
cool stuff in society and whatever do
you guys feel a little bit you guys feel
a little bit of an obligation almost to
like I don't know like like like you
know we're talking about community a lot
and I feel like you know until I really
started talking about and started
feeling it myself and started you know
like being allowing myself to be a
person in this community where I live
you know like allowing myself to be like
hey Jake it's okay that
sometimes you know ya brush your teeth
yet and you're walking down to the PIO
box
you know like to me I know that sounds
silly I know that's not community but
but but but but to me that's like a
little bit it feels a little more like
home to me to someone my upbringing
little things like that make it feel
like home
yeah and I think that community is is is
built within each of us of course but
there's an overlying structure that
we're all building and I think that that
now more than ever is an important time
for us to look at like hey our community
thing because of all these new things
all this internet and whatever is a
little bit different than it used to be
do you think community is amplified
identity like like identity like in
multiple people or do you think it's
more of just like multiple you know
different people being able to make it
work
Jake Jake let let me go off that yeah so
this whole time that we've been hanging
out doing band stuff doing friends stuff
Eric has really been introducing to me
the idea of community and so of you and
so is Jake and like I at first I didn't
know what it meant it was just a word
you know community that's a group of
people living together for a common goal
whatever but I I I've gone out to eat
with you guys gone to the store with you
guys gone on walks gone did like our
beach trip wonderful just like community
to me it was like when we go in those
mom-and-pop restaurants and maybe they
they throw in an extra fry for us or
something like that and we we just look
them in the eyes and go wow I appreciate
you thank you so much and ring in your
fries there's an onion ring it Wow I
appreciate you thank you so much even
even on the way out of your gas station
after buying a Red Bull just being like
hey I appreciate you hope you have a
great day to me that's community yeah
yeah see you're a person I think that it
is very important I think that I mean
we've extensively talked about community
I think that the most important thing to
narrow this down is its community is
within all of us and it's it's all our
responsibility every
single-person if you're a human in this
world the community that surrounds you
whether that's the people immediately
around you or the people on the internet
that share the same things that you're
into you know whether it's the band
mates that you hang out with whether
it's the people that are looking up to
you whether it's the young kids whether
it's the people who are same age as you
who are in the same community
you you kind of have a responsibility so
I think just knowing that that that at
all times you are whatever you're doing
you're building a community what
community you're gonna build definitely
I want to touch on this um back to the
community thing like like you were just
saying the the oddest thing to me was
after a couple shows that we've done
some guys and girls that have never seen
before in my entire life and this is not
me being like big-headed or anything
like that it's just like community
things like they've taken the time to
come up to me and be genuine be like hey
I really like what you guys did up there
that sounded good yeah and I would just
be like instead of just really oh yeah I
know
just feeling oh thank you thank you
maybe shake their hand give them a hug
if they want it you know just be like
hey thanks for coming out like that's
awesome glad to meet you man and then
just like just like being as roastin we
talked about this a lot and just as like
as Eric and Jake and Jake and Jake we
talk about this a lot is just like being
incredibly genuine up to the microphone
you know that's incredibly silent is
just the look on his face this edit is
gonna take me a really long time being
incredibly genuine as people and this
goes back to buying a Red Bull at the
gas station and looking the person in
the eyes and maybe making more than
small talk you know and to go off as
being genuine thing to tie it all the
way back to I was saying about like
getting your start honestly musically
and stuff like I've made so many
mistakes like the only reason why this
feels good right now and why we're doing
the right thing is because I've done the
wrong thing constant oh yeah okay like
like like like it's a learning curve
it's a like this community is also a
part of my
personal maturity right one thing I
think that a lot of people you know in
my small teachings and I do like a
little bit of coaching for a few people
the the huge jump for a lot of people is
realizing like that realizing that they
can even improve right realizing
realizing that that they're even in the
place to where they can be like oh I am
the mentor people are looking up to me
that was that would be hard to see how
to improve because as creators we are
spoiled in the sense that there's a
gauge of good and bad and we're in a
realm of talent ooh you know yeah I
could III I feel great sympathy towards
people that don't have a creative outlet
in this and not like a oh I feel so
sorry but it's just like I don't know
how I could cope with certain emotions
without doing music and so they have to
find it so that's why people find other
mediums that are really well like other
like like it's not like some people do
you like like the adult water coloring
books and stuff and like they have to do
it every night like I know I think a
couple of people I've been talking to
about that over the weekend and stuff
it's such a cool outlet defined by the
way right something made me pick up a
paintbrush for once but it's something
that's like not too hard as far as like
the skill level needed but you're
getting something out and there's
something about a creative medium no
matter how low that scale is that really
is processing something you know we have
an inherent need to be creative and I
think even like something like as to me
like as a musician and like totally like
I think it's like right brain like
totally the artist feeling sort of
mentality way of feeling up my human
experience
like I even view construction workers
and architects as artists as well it's
like that is that is their way yeah
mathematical artist that is they're like
like people who like fractal geometry
like construction workers are doing no I
don't think construction workers are
there factors like theoretical math like
it's not real like
like I'm gonna get like way far out here
right now but like mute like music isn't
real like it is but it isn't right
because because listen to this because
because I can listen to a song and I'm
like this is the greatest song that ever
exists and Jake Wilson can listen to a
song and be like this song [__] sucks
hey just like that I can look at a
painting and be like this painting sucks
dick and then Eric and look at the pain
thing like oh this is my favorite
painting of all time you know what I'm
trying to say he's got a great way
bottle for this though I watched a
four-part jazz documentary at the age of
17 for the first two episodes were it's
so important because it rooted something
like I got a weird teenage age this is
like when I watched claymation
documentaries at age 17 like like like
like the first two episodes were about
these West Coast Swing guys where it's
all about learning the tradition of
something like you guys Teddy Coltrane
you gotta learn that swing you got to
stay home with that stuff right the East
Coast in the other times they like and
and you're like okay that's that's not
nice and stuff like that and it's like
well why
like like what white wire why are you
guys so aggressive about what other
people it's like this because everyone's
saying they're artists and they're wrong
and I say okay what's going on
and in this guy in this interview goes
look look not everyone says any
expression can be art and that's [__]
[__] it's guys like smoking a
cigarette and he's just like just heated
right which is what all East Coast jazz
musicians are like I feel like probably
David Byrne you probably love that [__]
you I love David Byrne but he goes
anyone he's like a baby like not all
Expressionists are a baby crying in its
crib is obviously expressing itself
maybe [__] to call that art a baby
in his crib crying like I bet he's
clearly expressing itself but you'd like
that but and and to be clear that's not
how harsh I personally think of that I
am quoting
house how like a Gris this man was about
corn yes if you like splattered paint on
the baby
I was going I in it and gave it cilantro
toppings but didn't eat it no no no no
just tempted you slightly yo Alan
Parsons Project took Edgar Allan Poe's
the Raven with a vocoder back in like
1970 what ever since Ellen Parsons man
you remember him from Austin Powers when
when a doctor evil says I call it the
Alan Parsons Project yeah but that was a
band man no no I did that like I gave my
grandma gave me an Alan Parsons Project
vinyl it's the one with like the the the
two ladies on it and they're like
wearing veils over their faces I don't I
don't know I don't know I listened to
the album and it was really weird
Alan process I'm sorry if you like Alan
Parsons Project but to me I just didn't
get it bro Alan Parsons he's a producer
and he made some of the best albums for
one he was an engineer Abbey Road
Studios for like interesting 20 30 years
of his career and he definitely did the
Beatles and he also he did like the year
of the cat and he made the eye of the
sky and he did all that became yeah Rock
listen guys to anybody listening to this
if you ever meet Jake Wilson out in
public he will put you on to some music
you've never known existed but you will
love it I mean like I've never even knew
him and he will tell you he will tell
you what year it was produced who wrote
it who produced it and you will love it
in in in a title and two sentences from
each of us if we're going to show
currently in our time like right now
with what we're currently listening to
won't be like individually what album
are you gonna show a person right now
like what like like like all of us let
me got to hear this go well if it's not
just an artist in the song is fine and
that's like right now Oh album right now
it could be something historic or it'd
be something you're onto right now the
idea of the momentum you currently have
the momentum I currently have Wow it's a
this is it is honestly it can I do
tie right now that's fine okay um wow
this is quite the tie and anybody who's
listening to this is gonna be like what
in the actual [__] Jake but it is a tie
between Mack DeMarco - the - yeah I know
Jake would like that yes yes the Mack
DeMarco - album it is incredible dude
because I listen to chamber of
reflection obviously obviously I've
listened to chamber of reflection I love
that song
MACT yes exactly no this Mike DeMarco is
like how would you explain it Jake like
indie almost it's a it's a gap-toothed
Canadian sarcastic exactly yeah
so Ivan listened a lot of MACT America
lately I got into the - album produced
in 2012
actually it was I actually my my period
for this album because that album I
don't think it came out in 2012 I think
it came out like two years later are you
sure I I've nothing to base that off of
other than I listened to it too many
years ago so it's it's it's a chamber of
reflection no no no that's not on - oh
there's the whole album I've been
listening to - yep like compulsively
listening because it's just like a such
a grab bag of like music like there's
some it's just him and a guitar which I
love because like chamber of reflection
like what most people know him for is
like so much different there's like
synth and drums about good old Viceroy
man but um what's the second artist you
have as a tie okay so as thing this is
really gonna throw people for a loop if
they know but it's no surprisingly not
it's Death Grips Death Grips the Money
Store and the first time I heard Death
Grips
I saw in YouTube the music video for
their song guillotine III know it's
guillotine but he says guillotine in the
song and I was like this is [__]
weird and it kind of sucks and I never
touched him again
and then my little brother actually was
like I showed him that song kind of like
as a joke as a meme he got he started
listening to them again he goes yo you
should really give them my little
brother he's he's so open musically and
I love him for it like he will listen to
anything you put his name is ty my
little brother yeah yeah you know what
funny story with ty is that anza doe our
last show I saw him and I was like
brother is great to see ya and like
funny thing is is like I'd met ty before
but the problem was as I thought he was
somebody else
totally blindsided by the hug and like
and everything I was like oh [__] wow
this is not this is not the David that I
thought you were this is not who I
thought you were but but we still know
each other so this is more than what you
knew but expected you know it was I just
take it we were talking about a year ago
and he was like hey I actually listened
to like a full Death Grips album and you
should really give him a second thought
and I was like it's just noise it's just
noise and yelling that's all it is
and so I actually sat down with some
good headphones and I listened to the
whole the money store album and the more
I listened to it the more I became in
love with it and I really think anybody
out there listening to this should
listen to the money store album
especially get got it got by Death Grips
it's so aggressive you probably will not
like the music it is like just like it I
have no [__] idea
experimental hip-hop at best its
aggressive as hell it's a your Death
Grips but anybody who knows Death Grips
and likes Death Grips is gonna [__]
love me for saying this but but Mack
DeMarco and Death Grips are definitely
completely opposite ends of the spectrum
yeah they are not the same at all and my
my musical taste is so across the board
it's so across the board I've been super
into reggae for like the past eight
years I rigged a Bowie for sure super
it's no doubt about reggae reggae is
like was your reggae before we go on but
who's your reggae like so revolution
revolution yes who else who else in the
reggae well because there's so many good
there's us for like modern tribal seeds
is absolutely killing it right now
so like revolution and like sublime and
pepper if your room they kind of take
the the more California reggae like
you've ever heard sublime they kind of
go that route like rock reggae but
tribal seeds takes like old-school like
Bob Marley Steel Pulse black uru just
sort of like more dub like if you were
to like like listen to reggae reggae
that's just make you want to close your
eyes right exactly
exactly turn up the bass like with
reggae is just like it's just super bass
groovy you're following the doo doo doo
doo and you say snoop lion yeah it's
like you know I want to listen back to
that because I didn't give it it I I
think I actually probably made fun of it
morning I think no matter if there were
moments where I was laughing and be like
this is [__] like hilarious or like
I'm driving with this like I was getting
high to all of it it was like 2013 2014
that's what that's exactly when I
discovered ray gasher
I went over to one of my friend's house
and she was playing revolution and I was
like yo and I was like yo who is this I
was like this is amazing and she's like
always revolution like and so I just I
got home that night and I put on
revolution Pandora and I discovered like
I was like wow reggae isn't actually
seen this is like back in 2013 yeah I
was a Greg a is like actually huge gold
so like in reggae there's like
california reggae which is like super
popular in the u.s. there's bands like
revolution i rationed pepper that you
guys like and then you have like a dub
dub reggae tribal seeds Dennis Brown
like super bass heavy roots reggae you
know so like my music taste is
incredibly varied like at the far ends
its Mac DeMarco and at the other end
it's [__] death grip you know what we
need to do Eric is every time because
we're gonna have a few roasts hand
podcast I would presume I'm some friends
I feel like we should make sure Eric try
to remember this we should always at the
time of that podcast which Beck what's
your fit what are you listening to you
right now because dude I know you guys
so interesting dude I know that you guys
would be so [__] different every
single time because I am you guys I I
just have to sorry Eric what were you
saying oh man I was just gonna give like
a special shout out to half and run
because like like Ben you showed me at
the beach that's if I would show
immediately right now I was actually
playing some of it on our way to get you
when we were coming from it I wasn't in
the car so we were crossing across the
Astoria bridge and I was I was like
having this allergic reaction if you
remember like I was not vibing with the
overcast and the bright lights them in
my eyes really look and and I just can't
we're left off there the water
reflection hits you dude that that's
part of it and the clouds are part of it
and I just get weird reactions to that
and I don't know how to explain it here
or diagnose it should I should go to the
doctor but uh right but I found my
sunglasses did I or no we didn't find my
sunglasses so happy but half half moon
run there fantastic man it's like you
listen to them you hearken back to the
Eagles your harken back to time you
never met him before
Wow yeah it's very much I would say it's
a very it's a very well done modern
other the best seventies music is so
interesting because there's even a song
like I'd say that they're most equal Z
song it's called Black Diamond yeah
that's on my playlist now you showed it
to me yes thank you
it's a mate it's just like it has no
embellishment it just is the song that
it is and you can listen to it and take
that perspective from how you hear it
but but it's just fantastic because they
almost understood that when they made
this song that that like we don't need a
solo we don't need a crazy like boom
boom but yeah but there's no big Louie
thing in that song but they've got the
most beautiful little like piece of puke
why I just think I just think that it's
like such good songwriting at its core
that I didn't need a lot right and and
and they knew that which which is almost
it's that feedback loop that songwriters
almost create when they make the best
song is this feedback loop like a song
that's really like I want to be your
lover by Prince has has just been all
mine so much lately and it's like it's
it and and I feel like he's encompassing
so many things from like this Jackson 5
to Steely Dan because of when he put
that [__] out in like 1978 in 1979 it's
like he's drawing from all these
different parts but then suddenly he's
like boom I'm gonna take them all
together I'm gonna play drums I'm gonna
play keyboard I'm gonna do guitar I'm
gonna sing and then he makes us one
thing you're like wow like how how did
that how did any of that make sense but
you just did it right you know tells a
new story completely told a new story so
so above all would that be your album is
that right now like it like if you had a
diamond dude I'd say black diamond
because it has an influence outside of
that song lyrically that speaks to
people who have like problems with
addiction and I mean it's spoken to me
and my own problems in addiction because
I've certainly had
with substances and I've certainly had
them with with ways of life and mostly
just falling into patterns of build
nests and yeah just just just routine
where where you find yourself so deep
into something that that it's you never
expect that it's gonna tell you how much
it doesn't mean to you know yeah but
like someone rebase me well what we're
talking about because I got so [__]
focused on my darkness picking an album
that like stuff like right now if you're
gonna show someone else like what's
gonna be right now
man I've spent a lot of time on that
black diamond dark way with that book
put that in Eric Nordine as a transition
he mentioned the new Bon Iver album okay
it's fantastic yeah that I come on
spokes so much to me yeah it's nuts dude
but I I want to hear your album mister
you want to hear my okay I was thinking
so a lot of times like based off of what
I know this is annoying to do I'm gonna
pick two albums but I'm also before that
I'm going to say that it's not super
specific right now there is a lot of
times where I'm very very into like
certain albums where I'm just listening
to it on repeat yeah so you know I'll
have those times but like right now I'm
preparing for a couple shows and I'm
doing a lot of like I listened to a lot
of piano in the background which
literally just on Spotify I do peaceful
piano shuffle it and I do that like
hours and hours day was I'm with like
cuz a piano is like your main interface
yeah
because that's what I've been learning
like I spend probably I mean lately I'm
spending seriously like 45 can I
distract your question yes because you
are someone who like you don't like
necessarily play an instrument but but
you play an instrument because I've
heard you play a piano and I've heard
what it sounds like but but you don't
consider I feel like you don't consider
yourself that person plays an instrument
I feel like you consider yourself a
person who presses buttons in the right
time in place yeah you know in
and that's so much in and of itself is
impactful like part of the musical as
playing an instrument as also as also
identifying it like correctly I would
have to agree with mr. Wilson here the
albums this is such a good thing so like
it's like because I feel like it's like
starting starting with an instrument you
got you got to have a goal right like
that's that's so important to have and
then it's easy to be discouraged when
that goal is not not as near as
previously thought
oh it's also easy to get discouraged for
me my biggest discouragement comes from
comparison right comparison of any other
musician even other instruments like you
wash a drummer whose bet is it great
even though my guitarist it's like I'll
be intimidated to talk to that that
really great drummer right there's still
I thought you feel like there's a
looming he's better than you musician
Phoenix Ginger Baker but the but the but
the point is it's like no matter at what
level it's like yeah like you you fish
we play it yeah you play piano yeah you
do
yeah I think a little bit of what I have
issue with is of course I understand
that it's not incredibly healthy and I
have to give myself a little credit
where it where I need it but there is a
lot of like I'm hanging out with you
guys and so like if you guys were coming
into the DJ world you're all three new
DJs you'd probably be a little reluctant
to like show me like or compare what
you're working on to what I've been
doing for nine years you know so so like
I don't like calling myself self a
musician or see I'm pretty weird
annotation on that but that's why I'm
sure you guys like like one beat that
I've made because like I don't know the
way of making beats I don't know the way
of like producing like like hip hop but
sometimes I make something and we're not
going to judge you either I was like I
almost didn't make the song I wrote
yesterday and I when you place a solid
time one through like it yeah so you got
here before anybody else didn't you
played it like you're like hey let me
show you the song and you played it so
solidly through I was like yes yes and
it was just like I was like I don't know
I'm not a song right I don't consider
myself a songwriter because like I'm not
new to music but I'm new to songwriting
like obviously because they they
I wanted to make a big shout out to Eric
over there be like because I think last
time we rehearse together like has a
band I asked him I was like I was like
yo I was like what do you think about me
like coming to you with a song or
something he was like yeah sure let's
hear it I was like alright and so over
the weekend or so I was just saying I
kind of sat down with my guitar and this
is the growth of community the growth of
community it's just like that's that's
another thing with community is like
being willing to listen to people what
they have to say like even if it's like
open mic stuff like hell yeah open mic
stuff definitely important goes back to
what I said earlier is like don't be
afraid if you feel like it should be
shared right with a touch of quality
control sure sure why so I think along
with that going back to but calling so
family or not if you don't start calling
yourself a piano player then where is
the standard where you officially do
start calling yourself exactly dude oh
my god calling yourself that so you
start taking yourself seriously it was
the last few years that I started
calling myself a guitar play even though
I've been playing for 10 years nice dude
III never wants to take that upon myself
because it won't work it and more
ambition from calling yourself that do
you think I I think so because the more
I convey to people that like I play
guitar but I didn't tell people I have
to preface later like oh I have this
also backed me and like like all I could
do was be honest and just say hey you
know I've done this and that but I don't
have experience with this because if
anything I just wanted people to know
like if there was something specific
they had in mind whether or not I'd
experienced in that because I didn't
want to be the reason for why that field
because that now that was so much in
herself sometimes yeah yeah I know right
so Eric what would you say cuz because
me I think of things so many layers so
I'm like if I were to say if someone's
like hey do you play piano and I say yes
intially is the second I say yes with
that yes just that one word to me is
compare like comparing I guess but but
but but like what what would I say if a
very established if Elton John said hey
Jake are you a piano player I would
never say
yes to me difficulty I get that scale
that you're putting it's this one si now
that I say it out loud it's oh no that
scale exists because that's what quality
control is when it's put when it's put
in a healthy mindset but how do we
manage a healthy but also so like Elton
John to manage how he plays piano and he
someone like Elton John late I mean like
I I know some what about his career I've
been a fan for a long time he he I mean
he bases a lot of what he can do off of
what others provide him and some artists
work like that like they like I mean
Eric last week was like hey I have the
yeast for something and he provided that
yeast and then it starts to growing to
like this new piece and and for some
people like Elton John who you think are
like so fantastic and amazing his gift
isn't it isn't what he does with his
fingers but but when you hear a song
like he hasn't written the lyrics of
that someone else has done it
but what Elton John has done is he's
taken words and he's made them fit into
a melody and into a pattern in a theme
that makes you realize like this is a
song he made Crocodile Rock he made the
circle of life he made all that [__] but
someone else wrote the lyrics with a
different purpose in mind and he brought
that to life and that's his purpose I I
think to keep in this exact metaphor and
to keep this conversation I'm so this is
a big full circle thing what I would
hope Elton John would do in the
situation if I won John says RUP and say
yes I'm a piano player it would be his
responsibility in a music community to
be encouraging towards you no matter
what your level is okay so so you're
feared insecurity so my responsibility
as another musician is to know that I
have fears and insecurities there for
other musicians do as well okay
and so if if you're really feeding this
community and feeding other Creators
it's like last last night I I was
hanging with a bunch of musicians I was
the worst one in the room man but I
still hung out and I had a great time
you don't I mean and in in
but I was also like a better guitar
player than some of the singers right
and so this so there is something so
they'll be insecure about playing guitar
all of a sudden right did you feel did
you feel the need to like maybe present
yourself differently to them than you
would to like like like if you're in a
room where there's a bunch of other
musicians I feel a little confused on
like I guess like you shouldn't present
yourself as some hotshot even if you
think you are but I almost feel like if
you're in a position where you know
you're the worst person in the room
you're in a good spot well that's kind
of like that's learning dude like like
playing with both Jake and Eric like in
in row Stan like like you guys are such
better guitar players than I am but like
never at one point have I felt like I
don't belong like like like you guys I
get that from you too I'm and and
definitely don't think that influence
doesn't glean influence from from skill
because influence gets influenced from
from any place at all and like I see
your patience and how you approach
guitar and and how comfortable you are
just make it these big brash like blue
just like a strum and I'm like I should
do that yeah I I should feel it out and
take time and give my bass you know
because the that's cool that comes back
to what I've said like 90 times on this
podcast so far it's just like like what
we all bring individually to what Rose
10 is just like we all bring an
individual piece to it and like like I
think a big part of what I bring it into
it's just like a mood I think you know
he's man Y so what will you guys bring
to it for me is like that sense of
responsibility carries to me like where
I see you guys succeeding in my opinon
any personal lives like how you carry
yourselves or how you speak to me or
like on the B strip like we had a really
cool emotional conversation and stuff
and I kinda like let out some stuff and
they're just like a really nice moment
and like that's the stuff that you can
provide beyond music and that's and
that's community deeper than then I
think a scale could do you know because
we're all there for the
purpose of kind of this idea of like
we're gonna play music together but then
that comes with its own expectations and
then if you're willing to feed into that
it kind of demonstrates your character
because whether you're good or not it's
like how much character do you do you
want to show and like that's that's
still a hard point for me is like being
able to be vulnerable you know but I'm
playing do you think playing this music
on stage and like the level of emotion
is helping you get to is is helping feed
some vulnerability I think so I
absolutely think so I I think I think
it's giving me more of an opportunity to
to just exist and kind of my own space
without it
I mean without expectation not not that
like any of my other endeavors make me
feel like I have an expectation but I've
I've started this like I I joined rose
at an in a point in my life where maybe
I had more knowledge on on what I should
be looking for when I joined something
and and when I initiate something and
and it's just like a point of judgment
and like I felt really cool about the
group of people that I was working with
and and I still do after all these
months you know it's like the two of you
guys and you Jake Ryan's
I mean it's a solid group of people I
had a friend that I really respect
musically after our third show as an
antidote I think and had a friend come
to me and he's like hey man I've been
watching AG music for like eight or nine
years now I gotta tell you the the team
and the people that you have around
yourself right now it just seems like
this is the best situation just like and
it doesn't mean like oh we're gonna it
doesn't mean that we're gonna make it it
doesn't mean that we're gonna be famous
it means that creatively someone that I
respect agrees with that like we were on
the right track I don't really care
about if we're on the right track in a
year I care about we on the track right
now
you know I do care that we're on right
now but like in the future but you know
the only type of looking in the future
that want to do is booking out future
dates then continue to work on ourselves
in the current timeline to like be
better when we get up to those days
right which is what you guys are doing
heavy I mean you have Eric as a
bandleader you have taken I mean this is
you know probably more inside scoop than
most people really care to share but you
have taken as a bandleader you've been
just sending out all these emails like
you guys don't have a manager to think
no you don't have like there's little
things where I'll help in and like dorky
ways you know but I'm not your manager
or anything like you're handling all
this like the songwriting and everything
like you're you so thanks so your dude
it's huge what would because a huge
thing that you're doing because you'll
you'll text me separate from the group
and we'll talk through these things
because there's a lot of weight that you
put on and it's a lot of weight that
needs to be put on them yeah it's a you
you wear a very heavy vest but it's the
appropriate vest it's what this man
needs and so you are the one who emails
these venues and you say hey we're a
band and we do this and here's what's up
you do these things and then you come
back to the room and you say hey boys
like like the like the Jake's are at
work and you text them and say hey I got
us booked here and I got us booked here
and before you know you have like a huge
Northwest tour going on you know so take
taking on all these all these things and
expanding them are you Eric how do you
think you're you're forming into this
this role of being a mentor and teacher
yourself I mean it's it's something that
like is something where like in my line
of work being like at the after school
program with Parks and Rec or working
with children like as a paraeducator
and stuff like that there is like that
gate that gave me like a different
lighter sense of responsibility in other
areas where my personal life need to
improve and it's kind of noticing like
if your personal life improves your
creative life flourishes too but I just
like wasn't doing that I I definitely
agree yeah this this being in this group
and being in the career like as a
paraeducator as well as like has matured
me so quickly like
24 years old like like like being in the
in the career path I'm going towards and
then like being in this group as well
has been like definitely been like
especially it all comes back to
community is like how do you want people
to view you how do you want people to
view you and Eric and I went out to
dinner the other night and he said
something that really stuck with me and
it was just like I want to be those guys
that can go into a place and people
recognize us and be like oh those guys
are really cool those guys really sweet
yeah like because like the sense of
community is beyond the music like I
like like we go to that like there's a
block like there's a bar a block away
from here that we go to regularly and
like being nice with those employees
regularly and like like we can walk into
any hour and it's like a little bit like
those guys these are the musicians with
the producer who lives down the road
it's important I like and they like us
right there's different you know local
places we go to and the like that we and
we're hugging the staff when we walk in
because they like us and stuff is only a
couple spots but but going back to what
you were saying and asking earlier and
stuff what I wouldn't say is as far as
like the leadership part the type of
teachers that I've had I've had a lot of
good models on how to lead
well musically being a part of that
stuff underneath some really talented
people in Seattle and working in some
larger scale things musically that were
much bigger than me helped me see tools
and things necessary like okay like be
like like basically how it's me you know
what I mean and then I'm learning and
learning and then learning with
quality-control to kind of put into
scale and perspective here right and
then with that I think the best way that
I became a band leader here was when I
started being like fully honest with
myself right I think I had to let go of
a lot of personal things I had to let go
of a sense of loneliness and abandonment
and put my self-worth into what I'm
doing here I had to let go of a love of
you know the
people over here and channel that love
into like he say I sent a bunch of
emails that night was those few days
were days where I could have just soaked
but instead of sulking and slipping back
a little bit it's like no this love that
I feel like I deserve to put into a
person I can put that into the work I do
with this band and it's music it's just
as important to me
it's just as important you can channel
it somewhere else absolutely you don't
have to just the sorrow of not having it
you can put it somewhere else and
there's all sorts of loss and hurt and
confusion and no matter where you're at
personally right now with whatever's
going on you are absolutely like you are
absolutely worthy and you're the way
you're feeling currently is valid and
absolutely does get better and sometimes
to get better you have to like take
responsibility and I think for me taking
responsibility of past actions
knowing how I've messed up in the past
and trying not to do that again I've
messed up past musically to like into
some business facets where it's like
okay so I don't do that again right yeah
so you take all these things right you
take the business things you take the
personal things you take the musical
things and you always um and you want
you want to always put all this stuff
back into it you know everything that
you're learning from different people is
it's part of a toolbox that you have the
the hard part is making sure you're
grabbing the right tool for the right
thing and sometimes but that's learning
is when it doesn't yeah dude dude and I
think that's something that we're making
it pretty apparent whether you're even
trying to or not I just realized that
we're talking about this is like if
there's any new listeners in our inherit
music community and you maybe you
haven't made the right decisions or you
haven't done the right thing like it's
like a dude we're we're we're with it
like where or if you're going through it
and you're like I don't know how to get
these feelings into words like dude keep
going
we're with you we've been there yeah I I
think that like just knowing you know
the vulnerability of of all of us having
gone through these things and having to
channel our energy in different ways and
kind of being you know like it like I've
had my fair share of suck I'm sure we
all all four houses like man oh just so
you can get better knowing you are the
one who can
better artists only waiting for you
artists so weird artists so weird man
like in that sense is like I've had a
couple things that I've put onto my my
solo SoundCloud where I'd be like wow
this is I put my whole heart and soul
into this and it gets like eight plays
and then I'll just like put something
out and people be like wow I love that
one hey my buddy said this is his
favorite song and like it's an
incredibly weird thing as an artist like
you're kind of stuck in like this
mousetrap almost it's just like well do
I continue doing what my soul says is
right
or do I continue doing what people like
to hear I think is I definitely think as
both men III think it's it's like a
tempering of steel because each song we
release we like to look at it as like
this kind of epitomizing moment or like
it's it's like the the crux you know or
the apex but that it that it just
harkens back to that hype culture of
like how how everything that you do has
to be you know like measured on the wall
like you're like 3 foot 2 inches god
forbid let's grab the pen and go stand
up against the doorframe you know like
it's just not that big of a deal you
know like we never focused a control
work through that it finally came into
human words yeah one thing I put into
perspective about how small I am is I
love watching your mom's house podcast
it's like the podcast Tom Segura has
with his wife Christine Italians and
right I felt like super funny and as a
side podcast he has with Bert Kreischer
called two bears one cave and they talk
about like Bert crush made at this point
and they like laugh at this forever is
like and they say and this put it in
perspective what numbers really are he
goes and he says because these guys are
like like very famous but even in
celebrity bottom tier and they said in
every crush goes isn't it crazy that
people with 50,000 big number right
isn't that weird that people with 50,000
followers actually think they're
influencers
not that that scent that's that sentence
[__] me up is he's a hype man Bert
Kreischer will sit there and talk about
how he he's [__] Vladimir Putin's like
[__] doorman and how he gets
first-class train rides but it's about
how he tells stories and and he
definitely exact I mean like he makes
funny points but they exist inside the
reality of the stories that he tells a
story there's just a point where like
they're talking about like Instagram
models would be like they do it they
feel like they deserve like they got
50,000 followers therefore they should
have this kind of a status and this and
that and it's like isn't it weird cuz
like because they had they have they
have like maybe 20 50 to 300 thousand
followers so they're saying that they're
influenced even with that amount of
followers is it not as great as they
think so fifty thousand eight [__] so
you think you have to have more but but
but but it makes you wonder like what's
what's the weight of that that following
that you have because because like we've
talked about with Rosa Tan having such a
small amount of followers it's not
intentional wanted II not at all right
it's its quality because the most
important thing still no matter why is
is this word of mouth when you're in the
moment and when someone says let's
[__] go I'll never forget when when
one of my friends up in Bellingham got
fainted because a lady touched him at
caps and so he left the bar and said I'm
going to Nappy Roots so he runs all the
way over to the wild buffalo to buy a
ticket to Nappy Roots so he can get away
from the group and I'm like hey come
back buddy
and he's like hey I'm buying your ticket
so we both went and saw Nappy Roots and
that's just silly random you never would
have happened to somebody who doesn't
know anything you just [__] said that
made no sense
my valuate your circumstance my okay
evaluate your circumstance your memories
I wish don't be selfish evaluate your
importance amen but my point being is
that we get caught up in numbers and so
it was nice to see that the line of
fifty thousand even though it looks big
to me
[__] meat meat meaning that it's
important like he said to have an impact
with what you have right like we we have
maybe like 10 to 15 people that have
come to all three shows which is what we
should show you and like in at the at
our second show show number two right
our music is only been out since our the
acoustic EP came out in August okay
people were like not a lot to two to
four people we're seeing some of our
lyrics to two of our songs and that's
when I was like oh like that's like a
real like listener and follower it's
like okay yeah that wilfer your second
show and for a little time like long be
like that's great that's awesome man and
so it's about building off of that and
stuff and having people this music is
not like super bouncy and poppy and it's
not like everyday tunes but I want it to
be something serious enough where it's
like they can check in with that really
this isn't meant to be bubbly poppy you
gotta love this but I do believe that
even if you don't like the kind of
always emotional stuff I guarantee
you'll be into how this performance is
because it's because of what we think
about it we bring it yeah because I feel
like we're all being genuine I feel like
we're we're all disciplined in the
moment which is for me like something
that I really value about this
experience is like an aspect of
discipline where like I almost have to
let it conform and it's it's more in a
musical sense and it's and it's cool
because I have an open mind to that and
because I want to I just want to
understand what it takes to do that yeah
you know in this setting and and and I
think it's really cool I mean and I
think other people value that as well
because it's it's not as put together as
they'd expect it to be well it's like
well you and Jake and Kara lips I've
been taking direction really well in the
sense of like I'll come like like what
the acoustic EP stuff like I think we
like we crammed like three rehearsals
until I go week and a half look into a
week before I first show because I want
to learn those songs and get them
hammered down and like you guys had
tendencies of your own previous
influences and I had a goal and stuff of
like what I had in my head so we either
found
compromise we discovered a new sound
excuse me or you guys were able to kind
of pick up what I was showing and that's
in and that's a discipline aspect of it
is like is just because that's what you
have to do playing in an orchestra or
playing in a jazz band is someone asked
to put something in front of you
yeah and you have to be able to
understand that like sight-reading is
such an high expectation of and that's
not a skill that I feel like like I come
from a choir background so like like as
from like I think I was in choir from
like fifth grade up until high school so
like like even even though I was very
young and like middle school obviously
like whatever you know you're young it's
still like musically it was very forming
to me to be like somebody who knows what
the music is supposed to sound like to
be like no you need to be playing addy
here you need to be singing like a
denote here and then for me to be like
well I don't know for sure but I'll sing
a D and then when we're all singing like
this translates into roast and very well
when we're all playing I'm playing a
deal but oh that's why I'm playing the D
there because when we're all playing
together this goes back to the vibe we
were talking about earlier it's just
like we definitely have to feed off of
each other I think so especially lack
lack of like air quotes here a full band
yeah like definitely I think our
strength here is our ability to sort of
roll with the punches and play off of
each other and and and collective
vulnerability that you guys have been
willing to go on that ride with me one
thing that I'm really happy about being
comfortable as friends with you guys is
that one thing that I knew I wanted and
had to do like this is like from the
early stages of creating this and this
is why that Beach trip is like I knew
that I wanted to like I wanted to I
wanted to get you guys bought in and to
buy into this means I had to be
vulnerable I want to be honest about
what I'm going through as a person
current past and forward in the future
and I want you guys to be able to put
whatever you're going through
emotionally into this as well so that
when we're playing it's like cuz you
guys aren't going through the same stuff
I am but I want you to still channel
emotion so it's like what was the last
time you felt this way though
you can kind of put yourself there
onstage and go through that with me and
I think that's something that like being
able to present the vulnerability
musically I think is one of the maybe
not contagious but like attractive
things about Rose tan live I think is
that like we did a show with Alpine
Grace and a bunch of other really Johnny
Franco Franco silver Hill this week yeah
yeah he's really good we got some stuff
coming with him in February and March
and anyway some other bands - I can't
remem now unfortunately but we were like
the only band without a drummer there by
like the go list like okay so like we
can scream then we can bring heavier
energy we can do some wild stuff it
worked out pretty well - like I mean
honestly just like having three people
just like I mean Eric is so unabashedly
just like I'm gonna put it out there you
know and that's great because you don't
want someone doing that who's afraid to
do that because if that's a disaster ah
they're like this [__] is not
giving it his all we could feel that
right it's 19 you could get this all
duty dude it's an emotion it's something
that can't is not words for it's
something that you're like oh I know
that this dude this is his peacock
feathers this is lions roar like this
dude is doing what he does
[__] yeah and you know that and Eric you
do that in in guys like Jake Jake and
Jake you both just like you guys just
glanced at each other and I just I know
I said at the beginning but you guys
just glanced at each other and you're
like I get it and Eric says do this with
his eyes and you say I know what you
mean and you just do it and it just what
about one of my favorite moments and you
were there for it I think he was like
the first antidote show weird there's a
song it's the third song an acoustic EP
and there's a lot of great get spoiler
if it wants to do live because the
guitar parts are a little more intricate
there we're all doing some cool stuff
that creates a nice melodic
orchestration and there's one part where
so Jake Wilson plays lead throughout
most of the set and I kind of hold
down the core of the song with some
finger picking or some good chords just
like with good full tone to keep this
moving and every once in a while I take
like AI solos kind of the wrong term
it's like it's kind of the same thing
every time but I guess it's a solo yeah
and and it felt so good the first time
that after the course what we're
supposed to end it I was like let's
let's do the instrumental again like I'm
better off broken yeah yeah I was at the
Eagles yeah they're spontaneous solo and
a song like that solo in right okay yeah
yeah yeah I'm gonna solo here yeah I
just started doing it over there like oh
we keep playing and we do not stop and
there is no stopping and awkwardness
like there's a just because you play
with each other and a few you have to
rehearse you have to practice you have
to put in these hours that make these
things feel like DJing you have to put
in the hours to make it feel effortless
when you're out there it translate in an
in and like this uncanny way to a a
practice regime that you might have
we're like you you get home and you get
yourself in this practice regime and
you're like I'm gonna do this but then
you feel like that that applies outside
of that practice regime you feel a
manifesting almost and you're like this
regime is finally like becoming part of
actually how this is executed yeah
nothing how I do the things that I
practice in private oh no coming up like
without me even trying onstage that's
one able to look this guy in the eye and
say and he's able to say like hey that
thing that you learned seven weeks ago
in your basement by yourself you're
gonna bring that out right now and you
say yep got it yeah Wow beautiful
beautifully put Jake that's like that's
like so much of the magic that like we
put into the rehearsals it's just like
we spent so much time rehashing and
redoing the same thing over and over and
over and over again we're like way yeah
it's just almost like it's like wow I I
don't want to play these four chords
again ever ever again and then like we
pull it out during a live show and we
see people bobbing along with
and we're like ah that gives it life
again why you know why we do that and
we've only been playing these songs for
if like a couple of months imagine
people who have flight do us like a hit
single like a whole like a career but
most people don't love their music that
long there'd be a way to find it there'd
be there is a way to find loving your
music forever though I feel like found a
way of course not I get sick of [__] way
too quick I think you can love your own
music I think it's about like performing
it where it's like like it does like
become a lose it loses its luster
sometimes you know but but inside and I
already I'm like I might kind of over
some of the songs were already doing
mainly because like I'm not in the
mental space that I wasn't when I wrote
them and I don't want to like drag
myself back but at the same time it's
songs that like that people don't know
like what's important about like the
thing about Rose Tana having it not be
my name is like now everyone knows who I
am that's who listens to Rose tan their
fortitude not everyone knows the story
so the songs that are sad are still
important to people who may need them
right now dude like like here's
something incredible rubies on board
okay it's like I I hadn't heard I think
maybe I'm an earlier but that one print
song yeah yeah and I heard it too like a
month ago and and some of these great
songs that have come out in the world I
just haven't heard them until like
months ago you know and and some of them
in the last few years and it's amazing
that that we can have that ability to
like just like feel like we've reached
the end of the line like ah this new
thing came out it's the coolest thing
everyone's been listening to it because
this tame impala [__] or it's like some
ariana grande and boom I can't get
enough and you feel like ah I'm so
dissatisfied I'm so empty because this
was the biggest thing that I had but
then you go and you find that someone
made a song like 20 years ago or 20 like
with like an album even like you similar
fun at me like oh god I have I have six
weeks of healing with this album now
like like okay
finding Steely Dan's Asia but here's
another thing was was finding a
classic rock but but Tears for Fears
songs from the big chair and then
Christopher Cross is an album which ever
had ceiling I think it was just a
self-titled album but this is all 80s
music man and and this has such an
impact on me but but the thing is is
that music like that that gave birth and
rise to like artists like Toto who are
still like permeating through Africa
yeah but even beyond that man it's it's
amazing
[__] in Africa it's a great song all
these musicians are fantastic because
they're they're all putting themselves
into something that they believed in and
and like they all put that into like
Michael Jackson and they made the
Thriller album right Toto their ok these
these people are timeless without
attempting to be timeless because
they're just saying they were time it's
how you have to create music we have our
we have our yeah our goals are [__] up
sometimes do these people that you're
talking about Jake Wilson are they
weren't trying to be the hottest right
now no they weren't and you listen to
them you listen to Steve Lukather from
Toto and he's like one of the greatest
guitar players and inner ranges of all
time and he's just like yeah I'm just
[__] there I love that [__] just like
a barbecue on Sundays i watch football
it's like what the hell what the hell
you what you it's it's so it's so like
um it's it's interesting to have the
wall of celebrity I'm taken down and
like a creative concept because the wall
of celebrity makes you think oh they're
up there and they had to do all that to
make this one in reality the core of
like writing something like is that the
same core that you're starting something
to for the most part and it's like
really imply then that and that's the
cool thing about music and stuff like
that now I mean grind like with
electronic production like like it is it
is like it's stuff is changing and
there's a future and stuff but I do
think that I don't know I don't know if
it's getting more popular or my focus is
more on it but I feel like like bands
are kind of becoming cool again and
that's not why us being a band that's
like something that I just like want to
have
and regardless of us being right I think
the instrumental influence is is very
important nowadays and I think it's more
influential because it shows people more
of what they're capable of rather than
what they think they're capable people
might be scared of instruments nowadays
yeah well it takes it takes time to
sound good there but about a month you
could have I could you can get a decent
flow and for example we want right
freaking now and getting instruments our
long-term and they are like I like I'm
it's something you have to enjoy playing
by yourself like it's something that you
have to enjoy just hanging out with
yourself like so if you don't even enjoy
hanging out with yourself for definite
what that means yeah no no it's
originally there's this listen guys like
like like I'm telling you guys right now
and I'm telling anybody that's like just
picking up a guitar piano singing for
the first time there's been more times
where I've put my guitar away pissed off
then I have put it away satisfied what
made you what made you grab it back out
there wanting to get better right
wanting to not put it away pissed off
not making that decision like this is
forever [__] are forever you just put
it away man whatever and then when he
felt that urge later right yeah like
just like even now like I like I'm
twelve years into it like I was playing
the other night and I was I was trying
to learn something new and I just
couldn't get it and I was like man [__]
this I suck and I put my guitar case
away and I left it alone I was playing
guitar today like you know well they're
like there's all those complicated
things you can learn but the song you
wrote is pretty simple with two chords
maybe we'll add a third one in there and
embellished it to the right level and
it's and that's all that needs right but
it's like but it's like having the tools
though to make that decision and know
that that's enough and know that you
could go other directions
like I think and I think that most I
think were the most important assets and
music is like having restraint and
knowing like like that is enough as is
going back to that half moon run album
there's a lot of moments there where
they have that perfect amount of
restraint or they have crazy
embellishments but the embellishments
and things that are happening
our low enough in the mix that they are
not overwhelming and I think I think
that comes from also working with good
producers and engineers who have ears
because sometimes instrumentalists the
other ones who are like I gotta crank up
that part I want to hear me more there
and it's like I love that part but it
shouldn't be up front like that it's not
the song like if you were a pain just
like just because you can paint 37
different colors doesn't mean every
painting should have 37 don't just need
blue and pink baby yeah yeah yeah like
it like a sunset is only like like the
most beautiful sunset you've ever seen
in your entire life it's probably only
about seven colors I mean if you want to
get super technical like like some of
your favorite songs in the world are not
incredibly complicated just because you
can doesn't mean sure there's words in
the emptiness yes exactly it's like
David guilt like if you listen to a lot
of David Gilmour from Pink Floyd like a
lot of his most powerful solos aren't
super fast and crazy and technical he
finds the feeling in the space I think I
don't think that people find charming in
music something I find charming Stephen
tack pointed out to me and I listen to
on the broken record podcast a little
bit that I I think there's something
special about albums that don't come out
to perfect as far as I get like like
like sort of like the bony bear stuff he
he defines his music as the records
always come out little dusty and
scratched I was like whoa yeah yep yep
that's perfect Hayley Hendrix dusty
dusty and scratch sound like it's a very
raw sound
everything's miked and recorded that way
intentionally didn't get any more
processing she pumps I don't know Lucy
Degas she went from a pretty raw sigh
like that
even her produced stuff has a nice
amount of like desperate see to it and
like necessity in the sense of recording
do you guys remember that one band from
the 60s that was like these sisters no
less and their dad said you guys are
gonna be someone famous someday but they
were awful and they sang a song about
their cat and it was terrible and it was
unlistenable but then they gained a cult
following
among among like indie listeners over
their years someone backed me up someone
find out who you were you are an
incredible library of music I said it
like three hours ago but like Jake
Wilson will put you on to music that
from a time period that you've never
heard of his music taste never ceases to
amaze me like he's a water and a TRS I'm
like didn't see that coming
he's a walking record store he is he
knows music I wish I could charge that
much he's a walking music story he is a
he's a music catalog and his brain and
he has put me on to so much music from
time periods that I was no totally yeah
no he Jake Wilson has put me on to music
from time periods that I thought I had
heard everything from and I'd be like
nah this song from the 70s this artist
from this album and this year and I'm
like how have I never heard this and why
do I love it now he's like he'll come to
me sometimes like the right time
yeah it's just like sometimes just like
like in the rare occasion where we
haven't seen each other in person in a
week or so he'll come up to me and be
like yo I got this album from 75 from
this band that I know you love and be
like how have I not heard this how have
I not heard this just sound like some
weird obscure album from this incredibly
famous artist they're just an album that
flew under the radar I don't know I just
wait did you find did you find that
being you suck man I was looking for
them I feel like it's a really easy name
but for some reason they just don't make
themselves apparent to me it's gonna be
like the like the Dixie Chicks
yeah probably the Dixie Chicks were like
the freakin tater tots all right so I
didn't want to say we didn't fully
finish I didn't want to wrap up here
shortly but I do want to say my album
real quick and then go to Eric's my
album I would say we're saying earlier
yes yeah okay so I had two albums yep my
the the first one is the Devil Makes
Three
I forgot the name of the album but the
song is change the rhythm I think I
showed it a couple of your chains so the
album up Devil Makes Three
it's whatever the [__] album that
changed through rhythm is long it's like
a red album it's great and then also
holes in our stories by Dylan Owen
because I do a lot of like spoken word
and poetry writing and his is very like
it's euphoric it doesn't follow like any
music figure it seems like like he
doesn't care about quantization he just
he's writing like as the words come it
seems like so it's double makes three is
that the band name devil makes three man
named yeah what's the song chained to
the rhythm chained to the into the couch
Oh
chained to the couch is that what it is
yeah oh shoot yeah I totally miss booke
chained to the couch but that's the
whole album is great and then also the
second album was Dylan Owen holes in our
stories which is just so great he's just
a very original artist he's like a
spoken word poetry sort of guy I didn't
want to go to Eric though I don't think
did we get yours
we haven't gotten Eric set I do want to
we're getting up here in time so we
round out a little bit after that but I
definitely want to get a good
explanation of yours Eric yeah I think
two albums right now that are really but
and they've come in and out of my life a
little bit the number one album and I I
know Mele hoard music and like don't
share with people because you share
music with a girl you like and she
breaks your heart and you're like that
they like that he found that side or you
or you share music in like all the
sudden people that you don't really like
care for you see them posting about it
and all of a sudden it doesn't feel as
valid to you anymore
you only mean it sounds like a horde
music we should delete it so but that
pretty much but an album that I've been
loving to share with people if you like
the band daughter at all I recommend
looking up palace and the album is life
after they're abandoned well great song
dude absolutely lyrics the all in
there's something about like the whole
entire album it's easy to go through
from start to finish
there's nothing offensive about any
songs sonically like you could listen to
it very possibly and enjoy that presence
or you could be so intent on every like
I took time listens like all to get to
har parts and headphones a couple of
Saturdays ago which was like a big
Saturday for me
and I just I just heard a lot of stuff
when I was like it's like law simplicity
but the simplicity comes together I'd be
good on like a long nighttime drive
maybe you're like a backroad always you
know I always come to practice it's 15
20 minute drive from my house to the
studio yeah yeah I'll put on pallets
kind of getting them like it when I want
to listen intentionally I can listen
intention yeah when I want to listen
passively it's great yeah it's
incredible and I just think it's some of
the best songwriting I've heard in a
long time
and then an artist who has two names
Giada can baths but right now I mean in
2019 Giada put out an album called
traverse' that really changed my life in
perspective on electronic music because
I don't really I've kind of fallen out
of love with a lot of it but he's pretty
original but it's a album under his name
Bath's ba ths as weird as it sounds and
the album from 2017 roma plasm all the
songs are almost like so high energy it
can be like borderline annoying but he
emotion he puts into something puts like
a crazy texture and his vulnerability
and his lyricism and His perfect
portrayal of what he's feeling and the
absolute 100% originality nothing else
is even close to what it sounds like
that's why I like I love suicide boys
back in the day because like what I came
to underground rap like there was
nothing else that sounded like them and
now there's I got much people imitating
what they have done right they gained
that original sound just like it's not
it's not a negative thing by any means
but it's back like I don't there is no
other genre that it's in and I get
similar it's like what and Bon Iver
should be in that list icon was amazing
and it is one of the most important
albums to me in my life but right now
I'm listening to Roma plasm my baths in
life after by Palace every day in his
entirety at least once does I just have
to say the sentence does the fact that
so many people listen to bone Iver give
you faith in humanity as a whole
yeah I think what my favorite things is
that weird I mean they do not get
and I'm kind of joking I guess but I'm
not there's a there's a song using I
love it I love it there's a song that he
wrote over the course of five years on
that album and 23 people worked on that
song with him which one was that
am i attracted really mm-hmm thing about
that song man within like like when that
song came out before the album and it
was a single two or three weeks
25 million Spotify streams this man took
his originality and experimentation and
he opened the door for that to become
mainstream in its own self the read the
fact that he's selling out the Gorge
Amphitheatre that kind of using it's not
an EDM thing it's not Jack Johnson it's
not john mayer you know like who's like
those kind of venues this is something
that is inherently sonically weird and
is in on his end intentionally this way
and we have an insanely he's built an
insanely large community and following
that agrees I'm just trying to people
agree with what we're doing do you think
at what point in bond of it but Bon
Iver's career was he similar to where
you guys are at has roastin his first
album or before yeah he talks about how
for Emma he went to his dad's hunting
cabin he was doing he went to college as
a jazz major and he played in a band all
the way up to his mid 20s and then he
quit and I was a very like naked feeling
for him and so he went to a cabin to his
dad's hunting cabin with like it was
small very small little pro too like
majek like like console not a computer
console and one mic and he stayed there
for three months and he wrote that
entire album and he won a Grammy for it
misconceptions because of because of
idolization Envy and and oh yeah and
being raw jealousy without operating I
think it has less to do with that and
more of a lack of realization of boy
kind of life they're living I mean
because anybody could realize their true
potential in this life and do something
fantastic like make a record or [__]
own property or clean up the bay you
know but they just don't
and I don't get it in and it's just a
sincere lack of putting themselves to it
yeah with the amount of people that I've
met who just have such a fantastic
talent Jake this totally brought me back
to something that Eric told me a few
weeks ago and it is stuck with me and
I've thought about it ever since he said
it
Eric was like yeah you can love people
and you can like we talk about love a
lot as a band and like all the different
kinds of love and like how you can you
love your bandmates you love your family
you love your significant other all in
different ways you can love people and
it's like it's not about feeling like
it's not always about just feeling loved
it's about how you show it - totally
totally how you show it it works
yeah it's it's work to show love effort
to show love to show whatever whatever
the love maybe show it don't just feel
it know something like I I have been my
I think consistency is something I
lacked in 2019 that's something I don't
think I need to bring into my life in
2020 to become a better person in
multiple areas I think I think not being
consistent and showing love is like what
like what some of the downfall of like
different personal things in 2019 and I
think going forward no matter what
projects are in my life no matter what
people are in my life and stuff
consistency is how I can be a healthy
positive influence in those situations -
yeah like like how do how do I show love
to Jake Rhines Jake Wilson and Eric
Nordine right how do I show love to my
mom and dad my grandma oh and most
importantly how I show love for you to
yourself - love to myself how do I show
a good cookie batter or like a pie sure
yeah it's like how do you distribute
that consistency really really quick you
really have this - that everyone gets a
good slice of that not to do it publicly
but we do it in the group text just
banachek and how is everyone doing yes
all the time
dude okay how are you doing we're doing
good I do great you know Kay in life
you're feeling good yeah how's
everybody's Saturday going hey hope
everybody has a good Tuesday good things
yeah mmm month day what still
they'll be New Year's Eve no [__] well
hey that's a great place to end on the
new year so going into New Year I think
that we dropped a lot of a lot of a lot
of important things I think the essence
of what we all talked about in this
podcast this was kind of the thing is
cuz I wanted to have these guys over
here to of course do like oh you know
who is Rose tan like what what's the the
secret behind this band who is like like
you know every song is seamed together
coming out with super good so there's a
lot of like new listeners there's a lot
of like new uptick so that was kind of
the excitement of it but but overall I
think the important thing that we did
here in accomplish very well is is you
guys are just some dudes we guys been
doing secret or just trying to just live
a fulfilled wonderful life and for the
for that it's it's for you guys that
happens to me with music and like seeing
you guys all grow so freaking much over
such a short amount of time I mean just
as individuals obviously as a band Eric
I have known you for the longest like
just seeing you as like one of my very
close friends grow as like a band leader
but just as a man I think it's just so
great it's in it really it's it's I love
to Buddy and I love all of you guys and
I love the opportunities that you have
given me by just coming here into my
studio and just opening your hearts to
this place down here and just saying
what comes out of it and I think then
that all four of us and a lot of the
people who are in the ripples in our
wake are going to pick up this torch
that with that we're all saying we
should pick up and say like hey there's
people watching us and there's people
who are are trying their heart out to do
what they want to do and by us doing
what we think we should in these little
moments and in forming bands and forming
communities and making change within
each of us
it's it's doing something real so I just
want to say B before Jake Ryan's
finished is that we want to be able to
do this very band on guess wouldn't be
able to do what they do without Jake
Ryan's opening up his generosity being
such a gregarious individual who who
supports this kind of forum and like
open a medium for people to come and
share their hearts and thoughts with
others
and it's like a blessing yeah someone
like him is here to step up and do that
and so yeah I mean very grateful for you
for for like what you do in the role
that you play in people's lives and and
wanting to learn more about them and
wanted to teach others about where
people are coming from
for me personally man I mean like I
guess you and me on the cover of that
acoustic EP for a reason and stuff it's
like I didn't rebrand the art with
Telesis stuff for a reason I just think
it's a very honest capture of like what
you know like you said like you you know
you see me grow a lot and it's like
there's a lot of time so I've come to
you with a lot of like grief or
confusion and whether you grew through
it or not you just told me it was valid
and I think like it just gave me
self-worth towards putting music in this
area and I think that's like what draws
a lot of people to it and stuff it's
like you helped cultivate the honesty of
whatever what this is that it's roots
you know I mean like it started here and
it started with you and me in 24 hours
trying to crank some mountain man yeah
pretty pretty good good EP and I hope
that I hope that what we continue to do
and what any listener continues to do
within their community is realize that
that whatever you're doing does have
roots and in those roots can be strong
and they can be they can be authentic
and you know I think that I just want to
continue to be proof and continue to you
know expand that the veins that that
that spread from our hearts to our
community before before we go I got to
do the shameless plug of our days anyway
not sure when this is coming out and
stuff but our first show of 2020s
January 3rd we're antidote Tap House in
Longview Washington with david robbins
and Mason John the next show January
11th that's a Saturday where I asked
áown brewing at Longview great local
staple were playing with their friends
in the wild is she heard a lot of
conversation about that recommend to get
out there to that one January 14th
we're gonna be doing like just some
low-key acoustic stuff at Willy Dix
first Street Tap House in Kalama a
pretty cool spot not finalized yet but
in the workings according to my friend
Jacob Westfall we could be playing the
Takoma commitment another June 23rd
right another Jacob January 23rd Tacoma
Elks templeman
minam uns that's a question mark on that
one be sure you follow us on social
media at Rose tan band and that will be
validated or erased soon then January
24th we're heading out to the eastern
side of the state at Ellensburg we're
playing at the Pearl a really cool stage
above a bar it looks exciting
my friend Matthew Usher isn't awesome
focusing our songwriter out of Seattle
and he'll be joining us and then the
thing about the community that I'm
really excited we'll be doing Rose tan
is hosting an open mic at antidote Tap
House January 31st now what this means
is that there's gonna be several
15-minute slots that we want you as
artists or as musicians - please come
fill time and we're not going to be
doing like a whole set we'll do a couple
songs in between for open mic errs and
stuff we want to hear you guys it's for
anyone man it's for anyone you guys a
spoken-word acoustic stuff we have will
have a piano set up there if you want to
come and play keyboard if you play any
other instrument come and show us that
this is your this is your chance to just
share what you do as an artist with the
community and study and you'll be
welcomed you'll be well get in front of
a microphone and speak from your soil
it's how I started it's exactly how I
started and I've been frustrated there
hasn't been a music community and I kind
of had this realization where it's like
well who else but us then man so please
join us all on October 31st at a Tap
House for that February dates coming up
and being finalized soon and we just
really appreciate you guys so much
iiiiii I am grateful that we were able
to even book a full month like that
I've just had and just have consistent
work and I'm grateful that I'm doing it
with people that I love and I'm grateful
that you guys as listeners are tuning in
here and elsewhere if you want to hear
our music you can hear out Rose tan band
camp calm and on January 3rd an Adele
we're also playing a brand-new song that
is unreleased so we'd love to see you
there for that so we'll see you in 2020
yes love you listener take care of
yourself this has been Jake rinds and
roastin do good do good and be good
junkyard love podcasts out
you